welcome to category five technology TV
gratam genus technology quinque TV
this is episode number 525 the second
haec est res secundum numerum DXXV
episode of season 11 it's nice to have
XI eventus temporum habere nice quod suus '
you here tonight sasha is going to be
Hic noctem fore Not
starting to get the cabling going on her
ut incipiens ab ea agatur cabling
new computer say they can actually wire
dicimus autem non potest esse novus computatrum filum
that up and Sasha yes I think we're
et quod sic puto quod Not sumus
gonna plug power into it and just hope
plug eam spem potentia amet
beyond hopes it doesn't explode what
Quid amplius sperare non explodat
else have we got tonight we've got
aliud est non surrexit nocte Comperto
you've got news stories you want to tell
nunc demum istaec nata nuntium fabulas vis dicam
us about those yes so here's what's
ita etiam hic quid nobis de iis
coming up in the category 5 TV newsroom
Genus venit in V TV newsroom
it's official if you have if you had a
officialis suus 'si tibi erat, si
yahoo accounts in 2013 it was
propterea quod esset Yahoo in MMXIII
compromised Apple is investing a seer
Lacus circumsedent periculo exponi iudicatur qui olim videns
investigating a series of reports about
De noscendis explorandisque seriem tradit
battery problems with some of its new
problems cum novum altilium de quidam
iPhone 8 plus phones invidious at CEO
Dum invidiam plus phones ad iPhone CEO VIII
says Moore's law is dead claiming GPUs
Dicit Moore scriptor legis est mortuus dicens GPUs
will soon replace CPUs in the near
et mox in proxima eros reponere
future you may be able to eat a robot
futurum ut possis manducare a robot
that will heal you or provide nutrients
vel qui tibi cura providere nutrients
and don't mess with Amazon a couple is
et non tatam cum duobus Amazon enim est
facing up to 20 years in jail for
adversus usque ad vincula enim XX annis
stealing over 1.2 million dollars in
furari super 1.2 million pupa
merge from the online shopping sites
confundantur in locis online shopping
stick around the full details are coming
ecce venient inhaero circum singula plenum
up later in the show
postea ostendo sursum in
this is category five technology TV
hoc genus technology quinque TV
[Music]
[Musica]
our live recordings are trusted only the
Vivamus nostri tabulas sunt modo confidebat
solid state drives by Kingston
solidum statu agit ex Kingeston '
technology revive your computer with
et computatrum technology tuum vivifica
improved performance and reliability
meliorem et reliability
over traditional hard drives with
per limitem agit durum traditional
Kingston SSDs category 5 TV streams live
V vivunt TV rivos genus SSDs Kingeston '
with Telestream wire cast and nimble
et misit uolucres Telestream molestie
streamer tune in every week on roku cody
streamer tune in omni septimana ad roku possunt habrotonum,
and other HLS video players for local
et alia HLS video ludio ludius pro locorum
show times visit our website category 5
V temporibus ostendit visere genus nostrum website
TV TV is a member of the tech podcast
TV tech Mass in TV est socius
network if it's tech it's here cat 5 TV
Si suus 'suus' hic feles V TV network tech
slash TPN and the international
exacuere vade et internationalis TPN
association of internet broadcasters cat
consociatione penitus broadcasters cattus
5 TV slash iai beat welcome to the show
V TV show ad VULNUS iai grata beat
this is category 5 technology TV I'm
V quod hoc genus technology TV me
Robbie
Robbie
I'm Jeff I'm Sasha how you been hope you
Jeff ego sum Not unde venis Spero te
had a great week this is episode 2 of
magna res II de hoc septimana
season 11 episode number 525 want to say
XI tempus DXXV res numero dicere vis,
first of all welcome to all of our new
primum novae salvete omnes
viewers especially if you're watching on
praesertim si vos vigilo a viewers
channel 33 in the high desert in sunny
XXXIII apricis in arduis alveo
California nice to have you here also
Nice quod hic etiam ad California
anyone who's been joining us through the
quis est suus et quis in veniendo
website giving a lot more views on
dans multum plus views in website
YouTube we really appreciate you joining
YouTube ut bene vos vere joining
us as well mm-hmm speaking of YouTube
nos loqui de YouTube ut bene mm hmm,
brittany marie sent us a comment you
Designed Marie missus es nobis a comment
want to give that one yeah so says first
Primo dicit quod memini dare
season 11 rocks great work with the new
XI rupes magno suo labore ad novum
graphics package and adds redo the show
graphics et adiungit sarcina spectaculum redo
might need to come with a user warning
ut postulo characters node cum venerit
though it would be great to get a heads
quamquam illa magna esse ut per capitibus
up to put on your solar eclipse classes
ad partes induere eclipsis
before you go to the one of the tight
apud te est enim unus de stricta
hand model shots on Sasha oh oh it's my
O utinam meam illud exemplar Not in manu ictibus exactis occidentes
new ring looking forward to season 11 I
XI tempore EGO circulum novus vultus deinceps ad
think I thought that you were going with
puto quod tu venis
the the forehead like lens flare you
a fronte ceu lens cum exarserit post te
know when you're watching Star Trek the
tu scis quando vigilantes in Star Trek
lens flare to create the effect before
cum exarserit in conspectu effectus creare lens
the show goes live always powder my nose
Vivamus semper pulveris nasum spectaculum vadit
right so I think I could just like lend
rectum et justum puto posse mihi placet commodare
you some little powder here thanks buddy
Buddy pulveris paulum hic tibi gratias
yeah yeah that'd be a great idea
ut esses memini memini magna
you know I thought it I thought you know
tu scis quod cogitavi cogitavi Scitis
what does a bald guy do in a studio set
Quid est paro in a studio et a guy calvitium
it's either makeup or you can actually
vel rutrum et suus 'vere potes,
get some special lighting that is
aliquam id est speciali comminatione
diffused in such a way that bald people
diffunditur, ita ut populus calvitium
can use it really huh so that it's bald
can vere utor is ut suus 'huh calvitium
people what does it do to the non bald
populus Quid enim operor non ad calvitium
people gives them skin cancer you're
et det tibi pelle cancer
useless questions Terry right hey we're
Mark inutilia ius quaestiones heu sumus
only one-third bald whoo oh uh three of
tertio modo nudum whoo Uh oh tres
us I'm like what do you mean I'm 100%
Ego similis nobis quid me vis% C
who's Harry
quis est Marcus
I said Star Trek and so I want to go
Star Trek ut et ego locutus sum
back because the segue is gone now we
quia totus iam retro segue
owned it have you seen Star Trek
quod autem vidisti owned Star Trek
discovery yet uh no have you have you
sed quia non est inventa uh habetis vobiscum
know here's the problem I can't get it
Hic est forsit scire possum non habetis
you can't get it I don't have CBS all
Ego non adepto omnia non CBS
access or even on their website has the
aut etiam aditum habet in website
first episode I you need subscriptions
Primum episode opus subnotationes
for those and I don't have any you need
ad eos, et non opus est tibi ut quis
it on their website I think it's just
in hoc website puto suus 'iustus
freely available the first episode I'm
primum episode sponte praesto sum
sure I try to require a subscription oh
Utinam sane studeo subscriptione signa
come on no I maybe it's all accesses
nemo venit ad me maybe suus 'omnia febrium
five bucks a month I spent enough money
quinque illos leones, quos mensem exegi satis pecunia
on other subscription services if you
si altera die subscriptionis servitia
watch if you're watching this in the
Si vos erant 'vigilate hoc vigilantes in
u.s. you can pick it up on Netflix
nos te potest colligunt illud in Netflix
that's right it was on Netflix I would
Et si hoc iustum esse in Netflix
have already watched it yeah so what I
ita quod iam memini spectatores
okay yeah so we said this is worth
yeah sic bene valet quod ait:
getting CBS all access for so we're
CBS quia omnia questus accessum et sumus
gonna do it and that's all that we've
et feceris omnia quae habes quod suus 'agnus dei
used it for thus far well is it worth it
quia sic usus ejus est, multo etiam tanti
that's the question okay it's Star
suus 'okay ut' quaestionem stella
Trek's like this is legitimate Star Trek
Legitimate hoc Trek ut de Star Trek
so it's worth it in that we feel like my
sic suus 'non dignitas is qui mihi placet
wife and I feel like we're supporting
uxor sentio amo erant 'supporting
the franchise right just the same reason
ius libertatis causa idem
that we went to see the movies even
quod nos videre etiam movies
though they were not well-received you
etsi non ipsi bene te accepimus
know I
ego novi
they were okay as a standalone thing but
nisi essent sicut standalone purus
they were not Star Trek plain and simple
non aperta ac simplici AVE
they had a different feel they were not
se non aliter sentiunt
in line with Gene Roddenberry's vision
in linea cum mens ad Gene Roddenberry
if you were an original series or the
aut si in serie
next generation especially fan then it's
tunc suus 'maxime fan generationi alteræ
not in line with that at all
quod non omnia aequata
that's true but they had to bring in a
Verum est tamen quod inferant
whole new set anyway we're getting off
set totum usquam erant eludere
topic so that's talked about your shoes
et loquebatur de topic suus 'vestri shoes
so the the TV show Star Trek discovery
sic in TV show Star Trek inventa
we've been really really excited about
habuimus realiter realiter concitatae
it and it really does feel more like the
et quod realiter facit sentire magis similis
movies than Star Trek they've changed a
Ive 'mutatur de Star Trek ut movies, quam
lot of stuff to make it feel like the
sentio amo ut diam mattis
movies Klingons are not Klingons
Klingons movies non sunt Klingons
there's subtitles to read in order to
ut illic 'legere subtitles Pellicula
follow the conversations that Klingons
Sequuntur sermones Klingons
are having oh we're okay and kind of
Utinam et nos bene habent genus
cool
frigus
I do know Stu the actors they did a
Quia fecerunt autem novi actores ad Stu
fantastic job of carrying that but okay
sed bene est fantastic officium portandi
so when you think about it the plotline
Cum quo putas plotline
of Star Trek discovery though this is
quamquam hoc de Star Trek inventa
before they had the universal translator
habuit ante universae interpres
so technically timeline wise yes yes
sic etiam sapientes et technica timeline
you're watching it before they had the
tu spectant ante se habuit
technology to translate for them so
Lorem transferre ea in
really you're seeing it from the
tu cum re vera de eo
perspective of the discovery crew okay
perspective of inventa bene cantavit
okay where they won't give it that I'll
non ego te, ut et ipsi in quo bene erit
give it that so that's what it was not
Id non tam dare
sci-fi and this was not suspension of
sci-fi et istud fuit suspensio
disbelief technologies that actually
incredulitate, ut etiam technologiae
don't exist then I'll give it that
Non est igitur Et dabo illud quod
right so we were looking and hoping for
sic et sperans quia rectum petebant
a Star Trek to carry us through because
Ave stella prae nobis ferre
it's been a long time since we've had a
quia suus 'iam diu youve habebat
good Star Trek yep I'm a next generation
Vidi autem ego bonus Star Trek generationi alteræ
baby
infans
Saru up on the Starship Enterprise NCC
Saru usque in Enterprise Starship NCC
1701 D Captain jean-luc Picard is my dad
MDCCI D militem Jean-Luc Picardicae eis Pater meus
so you know this is this me yeah
scis me haec et haec yeah
they raised me buddy yep well that was
Donec erexit se bene esse yep
my first childhood crush you had a crush
prima pueritia contundito te mihi machinam
on the crush yeah oh yeah nice we had a
Gaudete in machinam habebat tincidunt O Yeah
big surprise though when we saw Star
quamquam magnis mirum cum vidi stella
Trek discovery and it was not what we
Quod non esset inventa et Trek
were hoping for okay and then why
Unde et bene optabant
we saw the Orville Oh Lavar Val we saw
vidimus enim Val vidimus Lavar O Orville
the Orville this is Seth MacFarlane
Orville in hoc Seth MacFarlane
we're watching this which feels like
qui erant vigilantes hoc sentit sicut
Star Trek yes it does it feels like Star
Star Trek ut ita enim sentit sicut stella
Trek
Iter
we know that Seth MacFarlane is a big
scimus quia magnum est Seth MacFarlane
Star Trek next generation fan original
Star Trek generationi alteræ originale fan
series man he made an appearance or two
aut serius vir comparuerit
on the next generation so to have him
sic eum in generatione
making a spoof we were expecting is
expectabat enim facit nos spoof
something else but right the spoof ended
sed aliquid aliud iure finita per CALUMNIA
up being really good it's not a spoof no
non est vere bonus est, non per CALUMNIA non
I mean there's there's elements of spoof
Illic 'non intelliguntur illic' elementis CALUMNIA
enos there are quick very minimal it's
Vivus est enim ortum using
almost like if we were to thrust real
paene quasi si nos per violentiam et realem
people into the next-generation universe
deinde ad universum populum, generation
right how would that be would they be
Ius id essent quomodo
the stiff morally perfect people or
a rigida vel populus moraliter perfectus
would they be a little bit on the witty
parum facetus essent in
side a little bit
paulo latus
you know fun-loving and mm-hmm flawed
tu scis fun-pia et tam mm-uitiosam colit hmm
slightly flawed anything with Seth
peccare contingit aliquid parum et quoque Seth centum
MacFarlane has some sort of flaw though
Quamquam vitio pars est generis MacFarlane
and that's what's funny about it this is
Hoc illud est quod super eam est, et iocularis
the guy who made Family Guy
Familia Guy qui fecit quod Guido
yes and continues to so my wife Becca
et quod sic tam continues est uxor mea Becca
and I are sitting there watching the
et qui sedebat ibi spectant
Orval where it sees episode 4 mm-hmm
In quibus res videt Orval IV mm, hmm
there are five in total so far as we
prorsus quantum quinque
broadcast this and I looked at my wife
respexit ad iaci hoc mihi uxor mea
and I said you realize Family Guy is
et locutus est Guy vos animadverto Genus
paying for this the special effects are
solvente pro hoc et specialis effectus es
amazing the gifts are amazing the
Mirum dona obstupefacere
costuming is amazing and the videography
Suspendisse vestibulum dignissim quam mirabilis est et costuming
and production is it outstanding even
et productio est etiam eximius
the script was really well done
vere bene factum est scriptor
outstanding yeah tastic somebody said to
yeah tastic dixit quis outstanding
me we'll SEPA sewed three was not as
te mihi non esse tria non sepa inde consuta,
good as episodes 1 and 2 and I said well
Episode I et II dicitur quod bonum et bene
here's what here's my perspective on
Hic est, quod hic mihi in perspective
episode 3 and I won't give you any
Episode III et si non dabit tibi
spoilers my perspective is they took a
Tulit autem mea non sit vastatores perspective
real risk to show us that the Orville is
ostende nobis realis periculum est ne is Orville
not just a slapstick spoof yes they
per CALUMNIA etiam quod iustum non slapstick
showed us that it is pushing to be
ostendit nobis quia non est propellentibus
something like Star Trek The Next
Next aliquid simile de Star Trek
Generation yes moral uprightness against
Generatio sic in rectitudine morali obligandi
racism and equality for all people
discriminationum stirpis et aequalitatem omnium populum
regardless of gender or sexual
regardless of genus uel
orientation or
sexualis seu
that's what it it shows which is very
ostendit quid sit illud quod
much in line with Star Trek The Next
in acie tantum cum Next de Star Trek
Generation and so then see you know
Et postea videbo vos generation nostis
seeing my comment they say you know what
quid dicis mihi sunt, cum comment
I think you're right yep episode three
Puto te recte tres res yep
they showed us that they're not just a
nos autem ostendit quod es non iustus
funny spoof it's true so we watched the
suus 'verum, ita per CALUMNIA ridiculam SADE
the new Star Trek Discovery we watched
Ave novum adtenti Inventionis
Star Trek
star Trek
we watched the Orville and the Orville
Et vigilavit Orville Orville
is coming out on top right nice I when I
et venit super me rectum nice quod cum
saw the first episode of war ville I was
res bello primum vidissent quod ville
expecting something not unlike the other
non exspectat dissimilis aliqua alia
move he did thousand ways to die in the
transire fecit mori in mille
West I haven't seen it
West non vidistis eum
okay and I was like okay I expected it
sicut et ego eram okay okay sum non expectata
to be something like that where was kind
quod aliquid simile sit in quo esset genus
of cheese okay
caseum bene est
well family guy that's what yes acting
Guido familia bene facere illud est quod sic;
more of that yeah but I was pleasantly
sed potius illius esse iucundior yeah
surprised to the point I turned off the
off punctum ad mirum conversus sum
episode it was one of those moments
paulisper una res esset
where you sit there going but I actually
ubi est eo sed sit in actu,
enjoyed that I have you seen that way I
libenter me vidisti me illuc
need to watch it tell us what you think
sit nobis necesse putas vigilate
it's Orville versus Star Trek discovery
suus 'Orville versus Star Trek inventa
which one feels more like Star Trek to
Ave ei potius quam sibi
you if you're watching this on youtube
Si vos es in hac vigilantes YouTube
or through our website comment below
aut per nostrum website Sententiam subter inscribe
otherwise send us an email go to
nobis aliter adire email
category five dot TV and you can find us
genus TV et dat quinque oppido Zywyecz distanti
by clicking on contact us
strepitando in contact nos,
alright we've got to get into it folks
licet necesse est ut in illam folks
Sasha are you ready okay last week's
Not estis vos bene paratus Ultima septimana scriptor
actually finish kind of putting together
actu huiusmodi compositione exonerare
the computer yes so we've got this thing
Etiam computer ut rem hanc Comperto
let's clear some space here Joe if I may
lets 'hic patet spatium Joe aliquid ut sic dicam,
all right and let's see if we can do
totum jus et videamus si non possumus facere,
this so this is part 8 you know we are
et haec est pars VIII scis hoc esse
going to if memory serves me correctly
si recte memini me ad
we're gonna connect the power
agnus coniungere erant in virtute
yeah and close the case and power it up
Gaudete in virtute causae claudebant
we're connecting the power powering it
connectens ea potestate erant powering
up there's the power supply there I know
Scio ubi nulla est potentia copia
see I've missed the unboxing well I was
Ecce Ego eram desiderari optime ad unboxing
here for the unboxing boxing but I miss
sed hic pugnis unboxing mauris
like old put it yeah so Jeff there you
tam veterum memini sicut Jeff posuerunt illic
go can you folks see that at home
ire potes videre folks qui domi
it's a beautiful built is you know what
Scis enim pulchra aedificavit eam
Jess
Jess
you could watch the parts of the series
cernere posses ordine partes
that you missed I know I could do it
nunc te scio, quod facere potui
cat 5 TV slash CPU 2017
V cattus TV VULNUS MMXVII CPU
that's where you go that's right alright
id quo nunc ire licet, quod iustum est
Sasha this bag here yes is chock-full of
Etiam hic est STATUMINO plenus sacculum est Sasha,
these modular cables right so as we get
ita ut vincula modularis haec dextra et dabimus tibi
into our eighth part realizing that hey
Nullam nostris animad octavae
we've got a wire this thing up that's
Comperto autem quod est aliquid in hac filum
really all we're gonna accomplish
omnes nos vere amet implerem
tonight it takes some time we're gonna
hac nocte capit aliquamdiu sumus agnus dei
get this thing done so all these cables
hoc fieri posset ista retinacula
come with the power supply because it's
ob eam venire potentia copia
a modular power supply excuse me while I
dum modularis differentialis potentia copia ignoscas
crush down behind a desk there we go oh
et post nos humiliare elit quis
by the way Jeff wore green today thanks
Jeff vestitos viridi hodie per viam agentes
I said no no do not wear greens and do
Nec non et virides gerunt locutus sum nihil
not wear green and he I misread that you
non gerunt viridi misread me et te
know what I completely misread it yeah
plane si quid memini misread
yeah there we go all right so this big
Unde recte memini enim magna sumus
stack of cables there you have it so I
stridorque rudentum ACERVUS eam sic est in vobis
need all of those no that's the beaut is
omne opus nuraen eorum non sit qui suus
that anything that you don't need you
quod aliquid non opus est tibi
can emit that's right so it doesn't use
quae corpora mittere possit sensibus et iustum est quia non utitur
up space in your child
locus autem puero tuo
ok it's not a bunch of cables to tie up
suus ok ut ligatis funibus fasciculum
look at all those keeps these sewn
Ecce haec omnia servat consutum
inside keeps a clean keeps the air flow
servat interius a clean custodit aer flow
high it's beautiful ok alright I have
princeps suus 'ok pulchram habeo Licuit
the same power supply in my computer at
eadem potentia copia in computatrum
home this is the 850 X from Corsair love
X DCCCL domum hoc est caritas de Corsair
it absolutely love it because I only
quia non absolute amant eam tantum
need the cables that I need keeps my box
necesse est ut vincula mea custodit opus est arca
so clean air flows much better it's
sic suus 'melior multa fluit aerem
awesome nice can we what we're gonna do
nice quod possumus facere quod amet terribilis
because Sacchi you've got to be really
nunc demum istaec nata esse vere quia Sacchi
hands-on with this and we're on a green
nos interim manibus uiridi
screen tonight where we're actually on
hac nocte in screen ex ipso sumus
multiple cameras and Sasha can't just
sicut non multa et Sasha cameras
walk over here so we're gonna fade to
ita hic per 'agnus dei voltus, ut ambularetis sumus
black and when we come back Sasha and
et nigrum et revertamur Not
Jeff are gonna be swap Aroo welcome back
Jeff amet non receperint Aroo PERMUTO retro
Sasha where are you that's funny
Not suus 'ridiculam quia ubi es
so I gave the bag we elevated your
sic dedit nobis elevetur tua lapides sacculi
camera a little bit to make you a little
camera exigua, ut tu paulo
bit can't believe how much we crash back
partem non credimus quanto nos back fragosus
down to reality in one show just like
in una re ad spectaculum sicut
that ok so are you ready to get going on
ut parati essent OK ita
there yeah
ibi yeah
what we're going to do here is just
quid acturus es hic enim est iustum
basically wire it up alright that's all
quod licet illud totum filum plerumque
we've got time for and that's all we can
Comperto quod omnia tempus habent et non possumus
do but if you're following along the
Si autem tu facis haec una est
series this is a great opportunity for
Magna copia seriem
you to see how just normal everyday
vos iustus videre quomodo normalis cotidiana
folks can build computers we're not
folks potest aedificare non sumus computers
computer builders we've never done this
ædificantes hoc computatrum numquam factum est
before I haven't built a computer in
antequam in a computer et non aedificaremus
years and you've never done it I have
Ego autem non feci quod tu annis
never done it so this is brand new to me
numquam factum est, ut hoc novam mihi
and so I need all I can see the guidance
et sic omne opus non possum videre ductu
all right
omnibus fas
that's what I'm here to do but I'm not
Hoc illud est quod me hie non facere, sed Im '
here to give guidance as a professional
quantum ad directionem amet
computer builder by any stretch and it's
fabricatur ab aliquo, et illud computatrum proten
really just comes down to hey you know
sicut est vere ad heus tu nosti
what anyone can do this as long as you
quis potest facere quod cunctis diebus vitae tuae
kind of have an idea of what you're
qualis es talem ideam
looking for what you need and and can
quaeris quot necessaria habueris, et quod potest
you know be reasonably good with your
recte tu scis esse cum bonis
hands and gentle with it so sack a
ita de quiete manus diripiendam
couple of things here right so first of
Habemus hic primum duo
all this is your power header 24 pin for
omni virtute tua hoc est ad caput XXIV pin
the motherboard right that's gonna come
quod suus 'agnus dei motherboard ius venire
off the power supply these guys here you
hic de potentia copia guys
see all these cables yeah those are for
haec enim omnia sunt retinacula Yeah
the case so these are different pieces
hae partes differunt casus
of the case HD audio so that's how you
ex causa quod ita HD quomodo audio
can plug in headphones like that we've
in obturaculum headphones non potest ut, quod weve '
got USB so that's already port 2.0 and
USB 2.0 Et surrexit ut suus 'iam portum
then we've got a USB 3.0 right here so
Comperto ergo a USB 3.0 hic est
these are all things that are part of
haec omnia ex
the the actual chassis the case ok ok so
ok ut gb ipsam causam est ok
your motherboard came with if I can find
factum est invenire non possum, si motherboard tuum
it here there it is what's called a pin
dicitur hic quod illic quod suus 'a pin
header and this is going to make it a
Header idque facturum esse
little easier for you to to connect all
paulo facillimus pro vobis ad coniungere omnia,
these things so do you want to just open
Vis haec labia iusta
that up
quae sursum
certainly all right so what we need to
certe ut universum jus quod necesse est
do is basically connect all these things
basically facere omnia haec coniungere
to the motherboard where they go so the
et sic ingredietur in motherboard
pin headers are part of like the power
pin es caput capitis parte tamquam in virtute
switch and the LEDs and things you'll
et switch sunt LEDs et si tibi placet vobis,
see this right well labeled so you need
ius intitulatum, ut tam videámus hoc opus
to find and line up these guys usually
et ab his ad aciem fere
the labeling is going to go on the
ut est iens in labeling
outside so it's positive and negative
sic suus 'bona et malis foras
but I'm already lost ok on your way ok
Ego sum ok, sed iam perdidit in via ok
speaker this is round 4 power power LED
speaker hoc est per virtutem IV potestatem DUXERIT
which is light
quae est lux
diode so this no Pat oh this one here
Quis est ergo hic nulla Diode Pat
no that's the reset switch so this is a
non switch ut reset ut 'hoc est,
reset switched and we don't see any
switched reset et non videbis
reset no this is turn it over you see
reset hoc non convertam eum super te videre
reset Oh
O reset
reset okay so that goes there there are
Bene autem dicitur esse ut reset
two
duo
okay so reset goes this way no no goes
Bene ergo dicitur hoc no Reddere est
flat looking at Oh like this yes got it
obtinuit eam, quod sic o sic respiciens ad plana
holy moly see this is why we budget
hoc est sanctum nigrum cur budget
eight weeks to this maybe that way
octo weeks hoc maybe illuc
cuz that's you know I'm so sorry things
cuz id est vos scire Im tam contristati sunt
just so yeah it's just gonna plug right
yeah suus 'iustus plug rectum et justum amet
on oh I'm just being too gentle sure
heu nimium mitis non me solum ad fideles
don't be too gentle folks yeah okay so
tam bene memini lenior fit ne
that's your reset switch with the ground
switch ad reset vestri quod in terra
and okay so now we've got a power switch
et iam ut weve 'got a bene virtutem switch
which is on this side yeah that's your
memini enim tuum est hinc
power switch oh yeah okay see how that
O Quam ut viderem virtutem switch bene yeah
goes
sequitur
yes yeah what else can you get on there
yeah, quod sic vos adepto super quod non aliud potest,
let's see what other cables we've got
videamus, quid aliud funibus marinis Comperto
these are USB and audio here we go power
Nunc vadam, et audio quae sunt USB virtute
LED power light emitting diode these are
Haec potentia DUXERIT lux emisso diode
the lights oh good the hard drive LED
O dura coegi ad DUXERIT luminaria in bonum
alright so this one here positive goes
Itaque licet hinc sequitur affirmativa
on this side and negative on that side
hinc illinc negativse
exactly yeah just line them up all right
memini prorsus sicut linea recta sibi
so this header just makes it easier
hoc facit facilius ut iustus header
because then he can just plug it right
quia bene potest iustus plug
into the motherboard so easy yep you can
Vidi in motherboard facile potes
do it out something like just easier to
facere sicut illud quod est sicut facillimus
get that okay next one is what this is
ut bene ut proximum quid est hoc
the HDD hard drive okay
HDD ferreus coegi bene
hard disk drive that stands for case
stat enim, quod si difficile orbis coegi
it's a nm - great alright with that if
suus 'a m - licet magno cum, si
that actually shows em not to activity
ipsa actio potest esse non em
or not
et non
ok so we've got to find where the header
Comperto itaque ok ut ubi header
goes on your motherboard let's see and
Sequitur et videamus in motherboard
don't forget now should I have a ground
Et nunc nolite oblivisci debet habere de terra
on here cuz ur
ur hic in cuz
we have not plugged in the the fan yet
non tamen plugged in a fan
so don't forget we need to put the fan
sic oblivisci non opus est pone fan
on the header' I'm going to just do that
in header, Im 'iens ut iustus facere
right now real quick if I may
verum velox ut, si iam
okay so that is just right down in here
Accumsan et iusto usque huc
we learned that last week we just want
si enim cognovissent, quod ultima septimana iustus volo
to make sure that that's on the
fac illud quod in
motherboard so the when we fire it up
et ideo si motherboard ignis
the fans gonna go right okay so the
Itaque pergentes purus amet nisl
headers what have we got
Quod nos got ut caput capitis
what's the header look like okay so we
ideo bene quid simile caput
see kind of how the pin looks so that
quam ut spectet Dalila ecce quidam
shows me there you go it's called panel
ibi ostendit mihi vade suus 'vocavit panel
on the motherboard it's only gonna go on
suus 'agnus dei ire nisi in motherboard
one way so Sasha do you want to go ahead
Not so uno modo vis Perge
I got in yeah
Yeah in obtinuit me
and it's only going to go in one way
et aliter ad eam tantum
yeah because there are pins that are
Sunt enim qui memini paxillos
missing from the right and they're
ipsi ius abesse
filled in on the header that was easy
super caput refert potuit
was it easy yeah fantastic
Suspendisse facile memini
look at that folks it's got the headers
aspice obtinuit folks suus caput capitis
on there okay so now we've got to find
et non est bene nunc ut Comperto
USB three which is this bad boy that's
Quod hoc sit malum puerum tribus USB ut '
how fast USB say find a port where you
quam ieiunium USB portum dico invenient te ibi
can plug that in alright USB one Oh USB
O quis potest plug in USB licet USB
three that is not it it's only gonna go
Quod suus 'tantum' agnus dei ite quia non est tres
one way because there's a kind of oh
Quis enim est unum genus
there's a ticky boo on it a ticky Bufo
illic 'a ticky in ea de boo ticky Genus:
let the technical phrase yeah all right
si recte memini verbis technicis
she's in okay we've got USB and front
in ipsa suus 'okay Comperto quod ante USB
panel audio HD audio and USB there you
ibi audio panel USB et HD audio
go are they also over here I don't know
ut etiam sunt supra nesciunt hic
I see a USB header there okay so we got
Video enim esse okay sic obtinuit USB header
we've got another USB three header
tria alia USB Comperto header
chassis fan header we've got whole bunch
Comperto gb fan header totum fasciculum
of stuff this guy in here gonna put the
huic loco effercio hic gonna
USB up there yeah okay oh wow sasha has
O bene wow Sasha habet USB illic yeah
never done a computer built but it
numquam aedificabitur sed adipiscing
pretty much other than me just lending a
quantum satis est praeter me iustus dare
hand here and there and giving a little
parum dandum huc illuc manus
bit of advice from what little
modicum quid consili
experience I have she's done this whole
Hoc autem totum factum est ut experientia illa
build so this is really the final touch
ut ædificem in ultima revera est tactus
hey Jeff like just getting the wiring
Jeff placet heus iustus questus de wiring
finished oh yeah and and then we're
O yeah, et complevit et sumus
ready to fire up the wiring is the part
praesto est pars accenderet Wiring
that I always love when it comes to
ego semper amem cum fit,
builds tedious
longum builds
you just want to turn it on yeah well I
vos iustus volo tibi bene vertere yeah
having trouble with this one what's
quid hunc laborantibus
going on it only goes one way right okay
nisi aliter iure ageretur est purus
so look at the pin pin assignment and we
ita ut videret Pin assignatione
see that there is a pin that is one away
vide quia ibi est unus pin ut auferat
from the edge but the one that you're
in ora autem quis es, qui
trying to plug into has not the same pin
trying ut plug in eodem habet pin
assignment so that port is not
ut portum non assignment
compatible with this front panel okay so
Haec igitur prima tabula bene compatitur
let's just uh oh maybe I just tried to
fiat scriptor utinam iustus maybe sum iustus conatus uh
plug in the wrong one
obturaculum in unum malum
I did and that would explain it plugging
Autem linamentis opus est explicare, et non sum
HD audio into USB good call
USB in bonum HD audio vocatio
holy there we go that was easy
non potuit nos sanctorum
alright what else have we got can you
quae licet aliud habeat ut vos got
find the HD audio we could look at the
respice ad potuimus invenire HD audio
the manual of oh but they're gonna be
ipsi erant 'agnus dei esse, sed ex o ad manual
around here somewhere
hic circa somewhere
okay we've got whole bunch of stuff
Bene totum fasciculum effercio Comperto
there it is oh you see you yep okay you
O bene sit tibi et videbo vos illic yep
get that alright alright there we go so
ut non licet ire, ut ibi Licuit
that's the front panel audio boom it's
panel, quod est ante illud audio BUTIO
on so we're gonna tie all these down and
in quibus et nos omnes astringimus amet
make it look nice and all that kind of
omne genus illud respicere nice
stuff later okay so the chassis fan oh
O bene et in chassis fan post supellectilem
this is the fan on the back of the
est dorso fan
computer right mmm that needs to be
mmm computatrum rectum quia erit ad opus
plugged into the motherboard so you're
SUPERGESTUS in motherboard ut vestri '
gonna need to untwist that and find a
agnus dei opus est rectior adstat, et non inveniam
chassis fan header which I see two of
gb header fan quod ego videam duo
them down there Oh see there's a couple
O illos ibi videre illic 'a duobus
over here okay go Sasha go go go
ut supra bene hic, ut vadam ad Sasha
I feel like if you would never make in
Si placet tibi ut nunquam in
one of those survivor shows yeah it's
Unus ex iis apparet eam memini
like I don't recall survivor building a
sicut nescio superstes in aedificationem
character twist tie this is TV take off
Supplet enim iste tollet gens moribus
the twist tie okay so if you're new here
Si vestri 'novus ut hic bene torquent per colligationem
I see fan yeah that's nice and close you
Yeah fan ut 'nice quod non claudere, et video
could probably left the twist tie on
fortasse relicto torquent vinculum
actually that could have saved five
actually possit salvavi quinque
minutes off the show oh oh goodness sad
O utinam tristi ostendo off minuta bonitatem
right big hands do this how many weeks
hoc jus quot septimanis magna manu
do we budget for this - oh I'm kidding
budget et non est pro - O kidding me
you just they do hope to fire it up and
et ignis in te sperant
stir
motus
installing the software next week okay
deinde septimana bene installing in software
okay are you on yes okay fantastic okay
okay okay etiam fantastic in vestri sint bene
this is done this is the motherboard all
omne hoc quod motherboard
the headers so that when you push a
ut cum impulerit caput capitis
power button and all that kind of stuff
materia tali virtute et ipsum
it's going to actually power up that's
suus 'iens ut esse sursum quod suus' power
the key thing right okay now we've got
key est modo iure bene Comperto
to get this up Sasha sorry I need to
hoc est opus ut Not paenitet me
upstage you with your computer okay
upstage vobis bene computatrum tuum
let's take a quick boo at this guy here
Hic Guido boo est vivos et accipies
so the headers on the power supply
Unde potentiae robur capitis
itself right these are going to power
dextrae se potentiam ad haec
the motherboard and all the peripherals
omnesque motherboard periféricos
by running the cables through the back
a tergo currit per funem rumpite
of the case so it hides it it hides it
ex causa quod ita sit celat celat eius
yes okay so we've got to find the right
Comperto quod sic tam bene ut reperio ius
one so this is SATA no they should be
ut hoc non essent qui DIABOLUS
marked
notata
I know these these kind of things but
Scio haec sed haec talia
SATA is your harddrive header right for
Quia dextera tua DIABOLUS harddrive header
power this is a molex molex we do need
non opus habemus potestatem hoc molex molex
because I saw a molex adapter here
quia semper nibh ut hic vidi molex
sticking out of the challenge
eiecistis de provocatione
most likely the LED lights right that
DUXERIT luminaria verisimile iure
was my guess
eius coniecturae meae
or it could be no there is no chassis
aut posse non gb
fan in the top so that is going to be
ut in summo futurum ventilabrum
the lights which are the most important
lumina quae maxime amet
piece in my opinion especially that was
pars mea sententia erat, quod maxime
a big thing that they've wanted right
quod rectum est a magnus nudius tertius quaerebatis
yeah exactly
exactly yeah
well we suspect that he does because he
bene nobis facit quod suspicantur,
wants the coolest of cool exact right so
velit iure exigere frigus et frigidissima
what I want you to do sash is grab that
quid vis ut faciam tibi est capto, quod constringes balteo
molex and feed it out through one of the
et illud per unum molex pascere
grommets just so that it's it would not
grommets ita quod illud non esset eum
matter which one well just yeah the one
quae res bene sicut unum yeah
that's closest and hide it away so you
id est ut proxime recondere
see that that's gonna hide that molex
videatur, quod id quod celo molex
away so that when we plug it in here
Hic est qui cum in obturaculum
it's gonna be in the back of the case
suus 'agnus dei in posteriore casu,
right see so it's very cool on little
vox tam parvo frigidissima est
wire where does that plug in so this
hoc est, qui in obturaculum filum Quo
plugs into the power supply right so I
ita ius potestas plugs copia
just need to get in there mm-hmm and
iustus opus ad in adepto-mm ibi et hmm
find peripheral there we go peripheral
periphericum peripheral invenire non venimus
peripherally that tons of them so I'm
sic Im 'tons of illos qui peripherally
just gonna have to wire in those kinds
sicut agnus ad filum in genere
of things so we're gonna take a really
ita et nos realiter accipies rerum amet
kind of quick go at this we're gonna get
'agnus dei adepto velox ire ad hoc genus erant
it done really really fast
uere factum esse ieiunium
through the magic of television we're
per televisionem et magicae sumus
gonna speed things up and then we're
quae sursum celeritate et sumus agnus dei
gonna we're gonna be ready to go
et parati sumus agnus dei agnus dei ire
super
super
[Music]
[Musica]
PCI Express is the graphics card okay
PCI Express graphics card est okay
okay on part seven so the graphics card
Accumsan septenarium parte graphics pecto
needs supplemental power and if you fire
supplementum si opus vim ignis
up the computer and there's no video you
usque in PC suus 'non video te esse
know that you've missed this particular
scio te hac maxime desiderari
cable this is what is going to give that
rhoncus id quod daturus
graphics card power so again we're gonna
virtus graphics card est adhuc sumus agnus dei
go out through a grommet Sascha right I
dextera mea egredietur per Grommet Sascha
can do this hands-on a little bit right
Hoc ius manibus parum possum
oh absolutely
o absolute,
[Music]
[Musica]
push on that just so it looks like you
et ita videtur quod incumbunt
did it all right so we've got the power
totum jus et potestatem esse fecistis Comperto
for the motherboard is this big fat guy
hic magnus pinguis guy est in motherboard
okay you do this one this is the most
Hoc est bene feceris
important because this is the power for
quia magna est enim potestas
the actual little motherboard itself the
parum se ipsam in motherboard
computer okay okay so I have to find
computatrum okay okay sic est invenire
where it goes in here first yeah so it's
Hic primum illud quo vadat sic Yeah
gonna go out the probably the same
probabiliter 'agnus qui egredietur simul
grommet I would think that's a good one
Grommet volo cogitare quod bonum est
it's well situated these ones here are
isti sunt optima suus
blocked by the motherboard so you're not
Non ita obsidetur motherboard
gonna be able to go out those ones okay
agnus dei esse possunt ones egredietur qui bene
man now let's make sure that you've got
Nunc lets 'certus ut youve' got ut homo
the right I don't know yeah I don't know
ius nescio nescio yeah
if these are oh if it matters which side
Si quis autem haec pars multum
you have well they looked the same
bene viderunt ipsum
yeah they look the same on on both sides
Yeah idem utrinque spectant
so except this one's got an extra clip
extra autem video praeter unum tantum
so this is the power supply side all
ita potentia copia undique
right okay and then in here where do i
Vbi et bene placitum et huc
plug that that's gonna go in for the the
Quod suus 'agnus dei ire in obturaculum est enim in
actual ATX power something so this right
ut hoc ius quod ipsa potentia ATX
here if that looks like the 124 pin ATF
si similis Dalila ecce CXXIV ATF
ah there you go yep he says it right on
A dextra Grat Vidi inquit
I'm seriously doubting my abilities he
Ego sum dubius mihi facultates se gravissime
just needs to go right in there okay and
sicut in jus habet aliquo eundi illuc, et bene
and I don't mind lending a hand I just
EGO iustus dare in manum tuam, et non sapiunt
want you to be like yeah please Dave
volo autem vos ut sis quasi Dave yeah
please dad this is this is sashes build
Hoc placet, hoc est Pater et murenulas et ædificate
and I don't want to be too hands-on with
et in manibus esse nolo
it it's just you know it is a little
quod suus 'iustus est parum scitis
tricky sometimes it's tough to to do
lenta interdum ancipiti captioni isse obviam ei ut faciam illud
when you can't get at it let's yeah here
yeah lets 'adepto in eam, ubi non hic,
okay so let's get that one on here now
ideo hic nunc in unum ut lets 'adepto bene
in this case could it have been like
quia in hoc casu potest esse simile
is there enough wiggle room to hook up
satis est enim, CRISPICO cella ad hamo sursum
the power supply first and then secure
Prius secure potentia copia
it yeah you absolutely could Jeff but
Jeff poterat, sed absolute et it yeah
there's a lot of room in here that I can
illic 'multus of locus quod hic in can
you know even meet with my sausage
et noveris in occursum cum farciminis
fingers you got it I can get in here no
et surrexit ut in eum digitos hic non possum
problem you you get in here no problem
et quaestio huc dubium
good - she's just yeah we just got to
boni - suus 'iustus non yeah nos iustus got
get that to clip in and for those who
qui sunt adtonsi in ut et qui
are watching this and you're just
spectant haec et tu iustus
walking in and saying what the what do
et ambulans in dicentes quid quid
these guys do when they don't learn how
nec scire facere guys
to build computers you are absolutely
quae facere omnino non computers
right this is an experiment in proving
an experimentum probatur quod iustum est
that even if you are not a computer
ut etiam si tu non es computatrum
builder even if you're just a normal
hic etiam si vestri 'iustus a normalis
everyday person that is just wanting to
sicut quod homo quotidie hoc volentes te
build their own computer just for fun
computatrum fun iustus est aedificare suis
that you can't you can do it you can
quod non possis facere id possis
absolutely do it
omnino facere
so that's on okay we're gonna flip this
ut suus 'okay in hoc sumus agnus dei flip
over here notice how gentle I'm being
hic animadverto ut Im 'ens in gentle
with your baby thank you mm-hmm now
Nunc cum vestris infantem gratias mm hmm,
there's the 24 pin header on the
illic 'a die XXIV pin header
motherboard there right it's only gonna
motherboard quod suus 'ius est tantum amet
go on one way but you want to line it up
alio modo procedere velis eam lineam
the right way and there we go perfect
et ibi via, jus perfectum, imus,
that's the power for the motherboard
quod autem imperium in motherboard
couldn't have done it better myself so I
Itaque mihi non potuit melius
think we've got everything set as far as
puto Comperto quatenus omnia constituit
power goes I believe yeah we've got the
Comperto quod potentia accedit credo yeah
all the headers on for the fans we don't
de capitis omnes fecerimus nisl
need a hard drive power supply because
opus ferreus coegi quod potentia copia
we don't have a hard drive we're using
non haberet ferreus coegi erant 'usura
an MDOT - right okay so when we
et mdot - ius tam bene cum
come back we're gonna plug this in we're
et nos sumus in hoc obturaculum reversus amet
just gonna turn it off we're gonna hope
tantum amet convertam eam spem sumus agnus dei
that it doesn't explode do ya a fire
ignis non explodat quin ya
extinguisher and if you have a fire
Ignis extinctor et si
extinguisher and we have coffee we're
et nos sumus in capulus extinctor
ready to rock
ad petram
I can throw the cup Cup don't go
Non possum non iactare calicem Cup
anywhere folks when we come back we're
huc atque folks quando reversus sumus
gonna see it either go up in smoke
aut ascenderet fumus videat amet
or light up one of the other was there
nec unum alteri lucis
are two options that's it don't go
quod illa duo non sunt options
anywhere
huc
whether you shop on ThinkGeek gearbest
si in vobis TABERNA ThinkGeek gearbest
B&amp;H photo video eBay or Amazon or even
Video Amazon eBay vel non B &amp; C photo
if you want a free trial of audible
si vis viva libera iudicii Dei
you'll find the best deals and support
youll 'reperio optimus agit et firmamentum
the shows we produce by simply visiting
ad producendum per solum visitare ostendit nobis
the shopping sites you already frequent
ad frequentes iam shopping locis
by using the links on our website visit
Nexus ad utendo in nostro visit
category-five TV slash partners for the
Quinque-genus TV pro sociis VULNUS
full and ever-growing list and help us
semper crescente plenum, album et adiuva nos
create more free content like this show
creare plures liberum contentus sic ostende
thank you for shopping with our partners
Wisi enim ad mercatum it cum sociis nostris,
and thank you for watching welcome back
et gratias ago tibi grata tergum ut vigilo
this is category five technology TV
Hoc genus technology quinque TV
great job guys yes now Jeff you switched
Job guys magnum Jeff et etiam nunc switched
back yes are we ready I think so I've
Et reversi sumus parata habeo opinor
plugged in a power cord into the power
SUPERGESTUS in virtute in virtutem spinalis
supply
copiam
they're just gonna plug the power cord
ipsi erant 'iustus plug agnus virtute spinalis
into an outlet I did okay fire that oh
O bene feci exitum in ignem
this is the power switch there's lights
haec est autem illic 'luminaria virtutem switch
now the power is oh look at that Aries
in virtute autem hoc o Virgo aspice
power to the motherboard oh the start
O virtus motherboard ad initium
button is illuminated Sasha it's like
button illuminatur Not suus 'similis
starting engine okay Jeff do you want to
Jeff bene incipiens engine et vos vultis
have the honors yes ready
Et accincti sunt honores
but I feel like Sasha shree no no I'm
non autem sentio amo Im 'non non Not shree
gonna do it one oh that's cool oh you
o utinam frigidus es unus quod amet facere
switch the colors right yeah yeah we're
yeah switch a dextro coloribus yeah sumus
gonna we're gonna pick red at some point
agnus dei agnus dei sumus rubrum in aliquo puncto robora
what I do I want oh oh look at that nice
O utinam mihi quod volo intueri quod delicatus
so when you push the button it just
Cum ipsum solum arationes
Christmas oh there's your red perfect oh
Class aptent heu heu est perfecta ruber tuum
it's off this is the first c22 from
suus 'off hoc est, a prima c22
Thermaltake so the case came with all
Et factum est cum omnibus causam Thermaltake
these LEDs it looks nice so that's of
nisi ut hae LEDs alius scriptor
course it's not gonna actually boot to
Scilicet ut tabernus in actu, suus 'non agnus
anything because we haven't installed
quod quia non installed
any software yet right there's no smoke
si tamen iustum est software est fumo
things are moving the Analects burning
quae sunt moventes per ardenti Analects
fans are spinning don't even hear it no
Non lanificio es fans, ne quidem audire eam
it's very very quiet it's super silent
Super illud silentium quod ipsa silenti
we've got air flow going the correct
Comperto aer flow ad rectam
direction so I'm feeling a good airflow
Im 'Sententia, sic inflatione venti editi partem bonam
coming off of that Wow
Wow venire off illius
yeah things that don't need to be
yeah quae non necesse est esse,
spinning or not spinning they spin up as
quasi fila telarum aut nere sunt
things get hot that looks fantastic
quae sunt calidum et adepto fantastic vultus
Sasha congratulations thank you thank
Not Aegypti gratulantes, gratias ago tibi gratias ago
you all next week we're actually going
deinde vos omnes erant 'actu agitur hebdomada
to plug it into a monitor mm-hmm we're
ut plug eam in, hmm monitor mm sumus
gonna start installing some software
agnus dei satus installing quidam software
we're gonna get Linux on there we want
erant 'agnus dei adepto ex ibi vis Linux
to get steam on there I don't know if
ut vapor est ad me nescio si
we're gonna be able to get everything on
erant 'agnus dei esse possunt ut in omnibus
there all at once but at least we're
sed omnes simul non minus sumus
gonna get it up and running yes as a
'agnus dei adepto is sursum quod cursor in, quod sic
working computer yeah that you built
quam operatus computatrum yeah built
Sasha built that so check it out folks
Not aedificatur ut sem look
in the meantime that's all the time that
interim hoc omne tempus
we have for this feature for tonight
quia in hac nocte habemus, sed haec factura
make sure you go to cat5 dot TV slash
facio certus ut vestri TV et dat CAT5 VULNUS
cpu 2017 to follow the whole series and
et seriem sequens MMXVII cpu
see how we selected the hardware why we
qualiter nos elegisse odio
selected each individual component and
et unaquaeque pars electa
how it was assembled mm-hmm so don't
Sic ergo non conuenit mm hmm
miss out on that cat5 TV slash cpu 2017
Pentium IV CAT5 in VULNUS MMXVII feugiat ut
over to our newsroom
ad nostram newsroom
Sasha terminus standing over there
Not illic stantes in Termini fano
eagerly this is like all you today
libenter hoc et omnes sicut est hodie
that's right Here I am
Ecce Ego quod iustum est
got the stories I do she's got the
illa surrexit et ad fabulas ego got
stories here are the stories were
fabulas et fabulis hic
covering this week in the category 5 TV
V in hebdomadam genus his covering TV
newsroom it's official if you had a yeah
NEWSROOM si officialis suus 'quoque yeah
cows in 2013 it was compromised bull is
boves de armento in MMXIII est suspectus est,
investigating a series of reports about
De noscendis explorandisque seriem tradit
battery problems with some of its new
problems novum altilium de quidam suo
iPhone 8 plus phones in video and videos
iPhone per VIII plus video phones et videos
CEO says Moore's law is dead claiming
Dicit Moore scriptor CEO legi mortuus dicens
GPUs will soon replace CPUs in the near
Et mox GPUs reponere eros in near
future you may be able to eat a robot
futurum ut possis manducare a robot
that will heal you or provide nutrients
vel qui tibi cura providere nutrients
and don't mess with Amazon a couple is
et a copulabis est non tatam in Amazon
facing up to 20 years in jail for
adversus usque ad vincula enim XX annis
stealing over 1.2 million dollars in
furari super 1.2 million pupa
merch from the online shopping site
merch a site online shopping
these stories are coming right up don't
talia non sunt usque
go anywhere
ivit servus tuus quoquam
Jeff Weston GEMA you're building a
Jeff GEMA es Westono ad aedificationem
brand-new beautiful website what are you
quam pulchra es novus website notam,
you're terrible actor what this where
Quid tu hic, ubi actor horribilis
acting comes into play you're supposed
venit in fabula actum esse cupis
to act okay are you building a really
re vera est agere bene tibi aedificationem
cool website are you building a really
building a vere frigus es website
cool website just because Jeff is
Jeff frigus website quod iustum est
confused doesn't mean you have to be
confusa, non vult te esse
visit cap 5 dot TV / dream host to sign
V cap visita dat TV / exercitum subscribere somnium,
up for unlimited web hosting for your
usque ad illimitata web hosting tuum
website with unlimited email accounts
habeant cum email rationum website
MySQL databases the latest version of
A tardus version of databases MySQL
PHP WordPress and more and even a free
Php Wordpress et magis libera
domain name registration it's less than
suus 'minus quam adnotatione domain nomen
six dollars per month so sign up today
sex pupa per mensis usque hodie ut sign
cat 5 TV / dream host this
V cattus TV / host hoc somnium,
is the category 5 TV newsroom covering
V TV newsroom genus est operimentum perditioni
the week's top tech stories with slight
in septimana scriptor summo paucis fabulis tech
linux bias i'm sasha Rickman and here
Linux pondus atque hic sum Sasha Rickman
the top stories were following this week
summo cum his fabulis hoc septimana
Yahoo is revealed that the major
Maior patet quod Yahoo
security breach in 2013 compromised all
contritionem securitatem periculo exponi iudicatur omnia in MMXIII
three billion accounts the company
tres rationes billion in comitatu
maintained
iudicium
that's a three-fold increase over the
quod oritur e triplici de incremento
estimate it disclosed previously the
prius detectum pretium
revelation contained in an updated page
an updated revelatio quae in page
about the 2013 hack is the result of new
de MMXIII est propter novam saginantur
information and the forensic analysis of
et notitia analysis de iudiciali
an unnamed security consultant
quod securitatem sine nomine consultant
previously Yahoo officials said that
magistratibus dixerunt, quod antea Yahoo
about 1 billion accounts were
super I billion rationes sunt
compromised with Yahoo maintaining
Yahoo periculo exponi iudicatur apud maintaining
roughly 3 billion accounts at the time
III billion rationes fere tempore
the 23:13 hack would be among the
23:13 et erit in saginantur
biggest ever reported yahoo officials
Maxima semper metus magistratus nuntiavit
wrote in the update we recently obtained
Ipsaeque epistolae, quae nobis nuper adeptus update
additional information and after
et post informationis
analyzing it with the assistance of
cum auxilio excutiendis
outside forensic experts we have
causis forensibus extra habemus experts
identified additional user accounts that
identified quod rationes user additional
were affected the report goes on to
Sequitur, ut fama est affectus eorum
reveal the jaw-dropping truth saying
tollunt se revelare asini verum dicens
yahoo has determined that all accounts
determinatae rationes omnium quae fecit Yahoo
that existed at the time of the August
quod fuit tempore Augusti
2013 theft were likely affected the
Affectus qui sunt verisimile furtum MMXIII
information has taken the information
notitia capta est indicium
taken in the heist may have included
ut sumptus includitur in RAPTUS
users names email addresses telephone
users nomina email oratio telephono
numbers dates of birth passwords scram
Tesserae plures dies natalis Scram
passwords scrambled using the week md5
Tesserae per diripienda una sabbatorum md5
cryptographic hashing algorithm and in
et cryptographic hashing algorithm
some cases encrypted or unencrypted
aut aliquibus casibus encrypted unencrypted
security questions and answers so that's
Quaestiones et responsa securitatem ita ut '
a big deal oh yeah so Dave had a yahoo
yeah a magnus paciscor utinam sic Dave erat Yahoo
account at that point
ideo eo loco
this is Sasha's husband Dave right so
Dave, ut iure de viro hoc, Sasha
now that hey your data was compromised
nunc heu quae data est tibi periculo exponi iudicatur
we know that your data was compromised
scimus enim data esset tuo periculo exponi iudicatur
right well it's I mean until he watches
bene custodierit usque suus dico
this episode right yeah and he won't
Hoc eventu yeah recta, et non
know that because before it was just one
scitis quoniam iustus ante
in three children may have been ok so if
Si tres fuerint in urna
you had a yahoo account in 2013 or
compotum vel metus haberes MMXIII
before so when I signed up for it as a
Cum enim et scripsi ut ante
kid and then never cancelled it and I
et non cancellatam eam, et hædum de capris
did all of my email all of my the the
fecerunt omnes filii mei de omnibus angustiis meis et inscriptio
information that is connected to that
notitia pertinet ad
account so let's
quare sic lets '
think about what that means I sign up
Suspendisse id cogitare pacto
for online services mm-hmm when I do
in online muneris, hmm, cum mm facio
that I provide my email address as a
ut meus email oratio ut providere
means of connecting to that service so
quod tanta ad connectens
if I ever forget my password what do I
si umquam mea password obliviscar quod ego faciam
do
facite
I click on forgot password and it sends
Mittit et ego click oblitus ignoro
right he-what a link to reset your
tui iuris, quod ad reset
password by email right so if the user's
Si recta ignoro email usoris
email account was completely compromised
rationi omnino suspectus
this assuming yahoo being the email
si haec inscriptio est metus
account at least that aspect of their
rationem certe summi
services then any malicious user could
et officia qualibet maleficiis user poterat
create a script that does forgot
partum a scriptor ut non oblitus
password on all these different services
tot officia password
PayPal online banking Twitter Facebook
Twitter Facebook online fretus PayPal
and gets that email sent to that email
quod non cogitur ad email Email
account and then is able to compromise
propter hoc et tunc in discrimen vocare poterit
the account so then all of a sudden the
Omnes itaque generationes subito
account is locked the first thing they
Et ideo primum clausa
do is change your password and that's
et quod facere mutare vestri password
done right so how do you protect
Quomodo ergo iustus tueri
yourself like how in the future now like
quid autem amo te amo in futuro
you had a yahoo account in 23rd right
23 ius haberes metus rationem
what do you do now there's so much
quid facis nunc illic 'tantum
potential for what could be compromised
potentiale quod potest exponi iudicatur
and even just thinking of okay what was
et bene cogitat quid
my yahoo password I can't even remember
Yahoo mea password non possum non recordabor
but was it the same password that I used
non enim idem password ut usus
for my online banking right I don't even
quia ius online Duis et ego non
remember my what my yahoo email was I
memento mei mihi quid Yahoo est tibi inscriptio
just know I had one right but it was
qui scitis justum et rectum non esse inter
connected in some way to your sonali you
quodammodo ad te pertinent sonali
had to provide personal information be
personalis notitia et providere quam
it your address or your phone number in
est oratio tua, sive in phone numerus
order to activate that account and there
et ideo ut activi
are emails in the inbox right that are
emails in capsa nuntiorum quae sunt recta
connected to you so how do you protect
Protegat te quomodo cohaereat
yourself well first of all you've got to
tum primus omnium obtinuit, ut ipsum te
change your passwords so hey if you had
ita mutare vestri passwords si heus te
a yahoo account back in 2013 and any of
rationem in MMXIII aliisque Yahoo
these questions are relevant to you if
huiusmodi quaestiones pertineant ad te, si
you're thinking maybe I did use the same
tu autem cogitas te utor idem maybe
password somewhere else or maybe I have
vel maybe password in alium locum habeo,
some services connected to Yahoo you
et quaedam coniuncta Yahoo
need to cancel that connection yes your
inrita oportet etiam, quod coniunctionem vestram
email account on all of your like if
Si rationi simile tuorum omnium
Twitter points to your yahoo account
Twitter propter ostendit ad vestri Yahoo
change it to Gmail or whatever it is
Inire sit quidquid melius est
that you're using now and change your
quod nunc uti tu et mutare vester
password on that service because you
id ipsum quod ignoro
don't know somebody may have already
nescio quis enim, ut iam
done the forgot password routine
Oblitus moris fit ignoro
and not done anything about it right it
Et licet non sit aliquid
might be a benign thing where they are
id ubi esset editus
accumulating logins and passwords right
vbi ius logins et passwords
right and then all of a sudden they hit
Tum subito sagittabunt ius
that's you know zero day if you will you
si autem tu scis quod nullus hodie
know you don't see it coming and all of
quia non videt eum et venient omnes
a sudden boom 10,000 accounts are
10,000 tabulae BUTIO repente
compromised how did it happen
aedilis qui factum
they've been working at it for four
si opus fuerit in quattuor
years right right okay so if this ever
ergo si hoc iustum ius annos bene semper
happens again yes should I just have
item, quod sic fit ut ego iustus have
like an email address that is just for
sicut quod est per inscriptionem electronicam
those things like how do you protect
ea omnia quam ut custodiat te
yourself because say email gets hacked
ipsum inscriptio dicunt quod sudatio, caedere tegmina
again mm-hmm do you jet like can I just
hmm mm, iterum tibi ut possum sicut jet
have like a random email address that's
sunt quasi temere id est inscriptio electronica inscriptio
not linked to me and any other it's
Non coniunctum est et alia
going to be like use it yeah so the fact
Per hoc ad similes usus Yeah
is is you just need to realize that your
vos iustus postulo ut animadverto ut is est vestri
email is really a central hub of
inscriptio est vere a central hub
information about you right so if you if
si tu dexteram Si notitia
you ever suspect that there is something
tu semper est aliquid suspicantur,
malicious going on you need to
malicious agatur debes
immediately change your password do
et statim mutare password
whatever it takes to make sure that your
quicquid capit tuis fac
services that are connected to that
quae pertinent ad officia
email account are updated to use
ut rationi sunt updated
different passwords for example change
Tesserae exempli diversas mutatio
your passwords it might help to just
ut iustum auxilium ad vestri passwords
always be suspicious and just change
et sicut suspectum mutatio semper
your passwords frequently yes yeah it's
saepe quod sic suus 'vestri passwords yeah
certainly there is something to be said
quod certe est non dicitur
for that
quod
kind of security through but but then
sed tunc autem quaedam per securitatem
what happens if if you get into a
fit, si vir, si in tempore
routine I've seen this in businesses if
In exercitatione mea hæc vidi si businesses
you get into a routine of often changing
tu autem frequenter mutantur ut in exercitatione
your password people tend to fall to
Populus tendunt ad cadere vestri password
simple passwords like adding a 110 to
Tesserae est ut CX ad simplex addendo
the end or two or three this is how
vel sic vel finis
people get you know why is password 1 to
populus adepto password vos scire quid sit in I
3 the most popular password because
III, quod maxime popularibus password
people don't like to have to constantly
semper enim quasi non
change their password right and if you
si recte mutare password
get into that routine you will
in tempore illo non erit exercitatione
eventually fall to the fact that oh I
quod eventually O cadere ad me
already used that password oh I already
O iam sum usus, ut prius password
use that password okay I'm just gonna
qui bene utuntur password Non sum agnus dei
add a 1 to the end right and that's
addere I ad finem rectum, et ut '
where I become no did we not cover is
Et facti sunt, non est ubi fecit nobis neque operientur
either a news story or something a while
per nuntium aut fabula aut aliquid a dum
ago I'm gonna say maybe 6 months ago
VI abhinc menses ante maybe Im 'agnus dei dicere
about the strongest password you can use
de fortissimum password vos can utor
is actually like three random words
est quoque sicut verba temere tribus
essentially what that feature that
Quid enim est per se pluma
you're describing was covering is what's
Quid quod tu describis operiente
called a password recipe right right
vocavit password est jus jus consequat
password recipe is used to create strong
password consequat est uti creare fortis
passwords that you will remember but
memento quod et tu Tesserae
nobody will ever be able to figure it
et nemo umquam poterit esse instar
out and computers even can't hack it
et hack computers potest non esse et
very easily at all right so that's what
Id quidem facile Habemus
you want to look at so if you're not
Si vestri 'non ut vos volo intueri
familiar with password recipes get on to
cum password ut nota ut recipes
category five dot TV and do a quick
TV et dat velox genus quinque
search up at the top for password recipe
a summo usque ad quaerere password consequat
he's busy
et est occupatus
thank you over the last six weeks six
six weeks ago tibi de sex ultimis
reports have come to light which show
venit ad lucem, ut ostenderet quod tradit
the new iPhone 8 plus phones splitting
VIII phones scissione inquiunt plus novi iPhone
apart soon after they start to be used
mox incipiunt fieri sine
in all cases the battery inside the
In omnibus casibus, intra in altilium
phone has swollen rendering the phone's
tumuit phone in phone, reddendo est scriptor
unusable it is not yet clear whether the
Non tamen inutile esse manifestum est si
swollen batteries are a few isolated
semel paucis gravida tumidum
cases or indicative of a bigger issue
maior exitus indicia aut casibus
the first report about the affected
affectus circa primam famam
iPhone 8 plus came from Taiwan phones
VIII iPhone plus ab phones Taiwan
with a similar problem and they have now
et similis est quaestio, et modo
emerged in Japan China Canada Greece and
Graecia Canada, Iaponia et Sina in emerged
Hong Kong in a statement Apple said it
Hong Kong in denuntiatione dixit Lacus
was aware of the reports and was looking
fuisse tradit conscientiam Dei et respiciens
into what might have caused the fault
quid feci in culpa
Apple's problems follow Samsung's
Apple sequitur simul solutio problematis Samsung scriptor
experience with its Galaxy Note seven
Nota cum suis usus septem Galaxy
last year hundreds of faulty Galaxy Note
novissime vitiosae annos centum Nota Galaxy
sevens were reported as faulty soon
mox hebdomades abbreviatae sunt relatum ut diverso genere vitiosos
after the device launched the scale of
launched ex scale quod post fabrica
the failure prompted Samsung to recall
Sanctus dabat eloqui defectum ad LG ad recolendum gratissimam
and discontinue the handset the problem
et relinqueris sola quaestio scelerisque
was traced to a design flaw analyst Sam
Cor defectum consilio ductos esse Analyticum
Jaffe says battery bloat typically
Jaffe dicit altilium pereat luxoriosa suis typically
happens at the end of a battery's useful
in fine fit utilis est de altilium
life explaining that having it happen
significans quod fit vitae
soon after a product line launch is
Post Lorem productum cum recta est,
troubling so hmm
hmm ut exterreat
the Samsung problem similar to the Apple
Apple et Samsung quaestio similis
realm was a battery problem right yeah I
realm erat rectum yeah altilium quaestio I
call it a design flaw that kind of makes
vitium tale consilium dixerim facit
a design flaw they explode exploded
consilium vitium explosa rejiciuntur
apples is bloating is bloating just one
apples bloating quod bloating quod iustum est
step below exploding like are we going
sicut ergo dicemus infra gradum exploding
to expect it if you take a lithium
spem si tuleris Calcium
polymer battery or some battery that
seu aliquam, ut altilium polymer altilium
expands
Expands
under use in a very very tiny shell
in usum ipsum apud minima putamine
because we are consumers and we demand
quia perussi sunt, et requirimus
tiny so get a big battery large capacity
ut magnam facultatem impetro a magnus minima altilium
little tiny shell small form-factor and
crusta parva et minima forma-factor paulo
you've got a recipe for disaster
tu facito clade possedi
so what could happen like okay so say my
et bene dicunt quod non ita factum sicut me
battery's blowing my phone's becoming
flante scriptor phone altilium scriptor becoming
unusable I don't know exactly how that
scis exacte quomodo illa non pendeat
how that looks but if I was to try and
quod si vultus fui temptare
squish it could I I could I make that
qui non poterant facere non potuit II squish
can I make it like even more dangerous
etiam simile esse existimabo illud periculosius
trying to you know drill a hole to
ut cognoscatis, conatur ad EXERCITATIO in foraminis
relieve the pressure yeah not smart no
refocillandam pressura yeah non doluere nihil
you can't push it it's not like it's
suus 'non amo ut suus' non urna
spongy did you ever have a blackberry
giosa tu semper habere rubus
no okay blackberry batteries were
nulla eu gravida sunt bene rubus
notorious near end-of-life for bloating
nam finis-of-vita notissima apud bloating
but because you can pull the battery and
sed quod possit trahere et in altilium
replace it it wasn't that big a deal
illud reponere, ut ea non multum sit magnum
people like a home about who's getting
ut de populo qui suus 'questus est in domum suam
bloated so they pull it out and put a
Et ponam illum turgentis trahere
new one in you could tell it was time
novam referre in illo fuit
right it happened with my BlackBerry's
iure factum est cum RUBUS
all the time but in this case it's built
sed tunc aedificavit eam semper
into the case you can't do that right so
in casu iustum est ut non possis
but yeah it absolutely it's dangerous
illud omnino est verum yeah periculo
what are some ways that you can prevent
Sunt aliqui modi ut ne quis possit
battery bloat then like in this case
deinde pereat luxoriosa suis in hoc casu ut altilium
obviously it's happening as soon as the
manifesto ut suus 'quam primum fieri
design yes as soon as the phone is used
Etiam adhibetur in phone primum ad excogitandum
it's bloating the battery but so look at
sed vide suus pugna bloating
you know like I have a case on my phone
ut si a me scitis et phone habent
so this is going to make my phone warmer
ita et hoc meus est iens ut telephono patriae amore,
and it's less heat dissipation than if
Si suus 'magis et minus calor dissipationis
it was just the aluminum body or
Erat corpore aluminium
whatever it is right so that heat causes
si ita fas calore
the battery to expand right during load
in altilium in in expand ius onus
so if you're watching videos for example
sic si vos vigilo videos exempli gratia
or playing games games are you know they
ludos aut ludere ludos vos non scitis
have 3d so they use a lot of resource
et non uti multus of 3d resource
power and and draws a lot of battery
vim haurit pugna multum
power and causes heat right so what can
potentia frigidum causas, et ita quod non potest recte
you do what can fly if it's a problem
quid faciam vobis fugere si suus 'a forsit
with the device itself then there's not
Non est igitur per se machinam
a lot you can do well I would say the
multum etiam ego dico vobis in potestis facere
first thing is the iPhone eights are not
Primum illud est: Non iPhone eights
that old so maybe return it under
quod olim per eam revertetur et maybe
warranty well exactly you've got a one
possedi unum warantia tam exacte te
year warranty with Apple and if Apple is
et si Apple et Apple est annus warantum
recognizing it as a design flaw it makes
cognoscentes faciat consilium vitium illud
me wonder if they'll provide an extended
Mirum mihi dabit diffusum
warranty on that not that it's been
warantum, non ut suus 'been
announced but it makes me wonder if it's
nuntiatum est autem magis miror si suus '
something that there be considering
aliquid quod considerata non potest
because there will be a legal liability
quia non erit legalis Rusticis
factor if they go thorry your one-day
si factor tuus vadam thorry unum diem,
posture one year and then the battery
deinde pilae annos gestum
explodes and somebody gets burned you
sudatio aliquem explodit et arsit
know there's going to be legal battles
Ibi suus 'iens futurus novi iuris proeliis
that come as a result of it so you know
ita qui ex vobis
I think at some point you're gonna see
Ego autem in aliquo puncto amet videre
Apple say okay we'll replace your
Apple bene dicimus nos reponere tua tibi
battery for free under warranty I think
altilium ad warantum per liberum puto
about these stories with the galaxy note
haec fabula nota est galaxia
7 where you know people had burnt
VII nosti in quibus homines incendit
pillows and things because kids you
et quia capitalia haedos
think about it so I'm talking about heat
calor et cogitabo de me
being one of the problems one of the the
cum sit unus quaestionum
things that caused this so you've got a
Hunc itaque quae domist
kid who's playing video games in bed
Qui hedum in frusta concerperet suus ludens video ludos in lectulo
right and then mom or dad come up the
Ius et pater vel mater ascendit
stairs and what do they do they shove it
Et quid faciunt rumpenda gradibus
under their pillow right and or what if
si quid rectum sub pulvino
you didn't generates more heat using
non amplius generat calorem usura
like a white noise generator while you
dum quasi generans Morsus
sleep right on your phone on your phone
dormiam ius in vestri phone in phone
and it's just constantly running and
et quod suus 'iustus currit continue
you're not thinking anything I don't
tu cogitas quod non ego non
have it under your pillow get an
factum est autem ut pilosam tua
external speaker yes as soon as you in
speaker quod sic externum quam primum te
case that under a pillow or something
causa quod per aliquid seu pellem pilosam
like that there's no way for the heat to
quod illic 'nullo modo sicut enim calor est
dissipate well there are some apps that
apps quod sunt quaedam atque dissipare,
will measure like if somebody doesn't
et si quis non ut metiretur
have you know like a SmartWatch you can
quia tu potes, sicut SmartWatch
get apps for your phone that you stick
ut in phone apps quod inhaero
under your pillow for the purpose of
Cervical vero ad tua
measuring your sleep cycle you can tell
amen dico vobis, cycle potest somnus tuus mensuræ
when you move and all that that's not
Nec moveat quod cum omni
great if that's the case right because
si id quod est maximum bonum
you're shoving it under the what do you
shoving quae in illo tibi do tibi
mean that the phone itself is hello it's
intelliguntur qui in phone quod ipsa suus 'salve
not a device no it's the actual phone so
et phone fabrica nulla suus 'non re
if the purpose like you're what you're
tu si quid ad te similis tui
trying to do to keep battery bloat from
ut faciam ex trying ut pereat luxoriosa suis altilium
happening is keep your phone cool mm-hmm
ut fieri sit vester mm-frigus phone hmm
so you take the case off is there
sic est accipere in off casus est
anything else you can do can you do some
aliud facis aliquid non potestis facere
sort of attachment where it dissipates
affectum quo generis dissipat
right could you attach something to it
ius tibi non esse quod attach
that would help no no no I really boils
Ego vere non non, quod se iuvare non ulcera,
down to just knowing that hey certain
heus iustus praestate scientes quoniam et certa sunt ut
apps are gonna run your device hot yeah
quae apps amet current calidum tuom yeah
I find for example when I use a VR
VR Ego uti a te invenio, cum exempli gratia
headset with the LG g3 it gets really
Lumen gentium headset cum g3 vere accipit illud
really hot because the processor just
quia sicut calidum vere processus
goes crazy now that device my device the
Nunc insanus est qui cogitationes meae cogitationes
g3 will turn itself off if it gets too
turn etiam in se accipit si off g3
hot that's annoying yeah smart feature
quod est calidum dolor pluma annoying yeah
right and maybe you know maybe there are
maybe sunt recta et maybe vos scitis
apps that can be added to these other
Haec apps addi
devices the
ad machinas
would assist with that if you're a
Si vestri 'enim sunt qui adiuvaret
battery developer for phones come up
Nam elit risus pila ascendit
with something really good because the
quod est vere bonum, quod
last two years are a bit tough and this
biennio proximo institutum esse aliquantulus et lenta
yeah this is the what it really boils
yeah hoc est quod realiter ulcera,
down to is we can start getting into
satus questus est ad nos in
politics and stuff like that where we
in qua nos sicut et rei publicae et supellectilem
can say you know how do you want to make
dico enim vobis quia potest quam vis facere
change stop demanding smaller thinner
mutatione postulantibus ne minores tenuioresque
bigger capacity because the the
quoniam maior est qui facultatem
manufacturers have to keep up with
ut enim cum manufacturers
consumer demand right and if consumer
aequum postulant et accumsan orci
demands has it has to be this that's
hoc est quod habet mandata habet,
what happened with the Samsung's yeah
memini quid per Samsung
they was trying to push the envelope of
quod cum conatur ad ventilabis involucro
technology too far too fast see I'm
technology est nimis celeriter animadverto ut Im '
waiting for them to deal with this kind
ut cum istiusmodi expectantes
of stuff I'm waiting to see solar panels
et supellectilem ad me expecto solaris tabulata
so to speak on a phone on the back and
et super phone tergum in ut ita dicam,
underneath the screen of the phone so
in screen phone ut a fossa humo operui
that you can have smaller battery
pugna posse minora
capacity but it's always charging with
cum tamen suus 'facultatem semper cornibus ventilantem
energy and everything so you can just
omne quod navitas ut vos can iustus
put your phone down on a table and it
posuit et mensam in phone usque
will recharge assuming that you have
si tamen habes in recharge
that technology I'm sure yes very cool
Im 'certus ut technology quod sic frigus ipsum
Jensen who a founder and CEO of Nvidia
Jensen, qui est conditor et CEO of NVIDIA
said at the GPU technology conference in
dixit in colloquium in technology GPU
Beijing that Moore's law is dead because
Beijing Moore scriptor legis, quae est, quod
it cannot keep pace with advancements in
cum profectibus in pace ut non possit
GPU design Moore's law is the
GPU in consilio Moore scriptor legis
observation made by Gordon Moore
hic observandum quod Moore per Cicero
co-founder of Intel in 1965 that the
Intel co-conditor quod in MCMLXV
number of transistors per square inch on
digiti quadrati ad numerum per transistores
integrated circuits had doubled every
Proin cursus duplicata omni
year since integrated circuit was
annus integer circumducta
invented more predicted that this trend
hoc praedixit, quod hanc trend excogitari
would continue for the foreseeable
ad praevisum in futurum permanere
future
futurae
however the pace is slowed down a bit in
sed in pace a frenum in veluti remora injiciatur
the subsequent years but data density is
sed subsequens annis data est density
doubled approximately every 18 months
XVIII menses singulis fere duplicatur
Wang says that since the CPU transistors
Wang cum dicit transistorum CPU
have grown at an annual pace of 50
crevit in pace non est de L annui
percent the performance has only been
quae tantum percent in perficientur fuit
enhanced by 10 percent he believes the
addita sunt X percent credit in eum
GPU will take over
GPU et praeter eum
according to hang the top 5 ecommerce
ut dependeat in eo secundum summo V Cras
sites in China have already accepted at
in Sina, in locis iam accepit
vidya Volta GPU architectures to support
GPU in Volta vidya architectures support
cloud services and hgx based GPU servers
cloud servers GPU secundum officia et hgx
have been deployed by both Lenovo and
et a Lenovo, et diffusi sunt
way
ita
Huang claims nvidia gpus are the perfect
Huang vindicat nvidia GPUs perfecta sunt
solution for AI based application
solution secundum applicationem ad AI,
suggesting he believes GPUs are set to
suggerente ille qui credit GPUs profectus est
play a larger role in certain aspects of
ludere maior munus in aliqua facies
computing rather than replacing desktop
computandi magis quam repositoque desktop
CPUs completely he showed faith in
CPUs ostendit quod totaliter fides
NVIDIA GPUs and claimed that they will
Asseruit se faciet et NVIDIA GPUs
be able to replace CPUs in the upcoming
Praesent in eros possint reponere
years
annorum
okay so just but for anybody who doesn't
sicut et aliorum qui non bene sed
know GPU versus CPU what's the
GPU versus nescio quis 'CPU
difference what yeah one character not
Non memini enim refert qua me ratione
even like it's just like that is the
simile etiam est sicut quod est,
difference used to CPU and then just add
et sicut addere interesse solebat CPU
that and it's GPU that is the technical
et quia illud quod sit GPU technica
term and now everybody who has no clue
et nunc qui habet terminum omnibus clue
what they are going CPU is the central
quid properas est media CPU
processing unit the brains of the
processus unitas in cerebris,
computer the GPU is the graphics
cum computatrum graphics GPU est
processing here yes let's go back in
Etiam vestibulum eamus hinc retro
time a little bit Jeff okay think about
Jeff bene cogitant de nunc exigua
computers the evolution of computing the
computers ad unitatem essentiae pertinet computatis
CPU the brains of the computer was used
Usus est CPU computer cerebella
for things like doing spreadsheets yes
Ita enim res faciunt Spreadsheets
running an operating system and doing
currit an operating ratio quod facere
those kinds of thought processes didn't
si non genere processus
need a whole lot of power realistically
opus totum a potestate multa rerum momentis attentis ducendi
in comparison to say 3d graphics so if
In graphics et si collatio dicere 3D
you're just doing spreadsheets and
tu modo facis, et spreadsheets
Microsoft Office and surfing the
Et superficies Microsoft Office
internet the CPU is the central
per CPU media Penitus est
processing unit the brains of the
unitas processus in cerebro
computer you've heard of like dual-core
audivi de te ut computatrum dual-core
and quad-core now hexa-core computers
et nunc, quad-core hexa-core computers
and things like that so you've got Wow
quia amo te surrexit ergo et rerum Wow
eight cores on your computer that's fast
quod celeriter octo millia metretas computatrum tuum
that has a lot of power right lots of
qui habet lots of multus of virtus recta
threads going in you've got you know
nunc demum istaec nata scitis relatorum in eo
eight cores that's gonna give you you
Quod ut 'non agnus dei dabo vos octo millia metretas
know several threads to go you know so
tu scis plura scire fila
thought processes of the brain so we can
ita potest cogitari processus cerebri
think about more than four things at
de rebus plus quattuor
once right but not more than 10 I think
X, non plus quam semel iure non puto
right but it does it fast so
sed jus facit ieiunare
perceptively it happens quite quickly a
subtiliter satis celeriter fieri est
GPU was built for graphics originally so
Graphics GPU ædificaverat primum sic fuit
think about gaming and how gaming has
et quam cogitare de forumque aleatoruml habet
pushed too
et pushed
like 3d and now virtual reality and the
3D virtualis re, sicut et nunc et
real push is there to create really
creare vere est realis dis
really fast what graphics right right we
vere ieiunium quod graphics rectam nobis recta
want high frame rates if my kids don't
altum frame rates, si mihi non vultis faciam haedos
have 60 frames per second on minecraft
in LX tabulae erunt per secundus in minecraft
dad's gonna hear about it so I remember
Pater eius est agnus ut audierit recordabor
what I was excited about 30 30 would be
quae est dolor de XXX XXX esset
awesome yep okay so think about this so
et hoc ita bene cogitare de terribilis yep
think about your four core computer
cogitare de quatuor core computatrum tuum
processor mm-hmm that's the CPU yep now
hmm-mm processus ut 'nunc yep CPU
think about a nvidia card you just put
puto vos iustus posuit card de nvidia
in a ten seventy in your new computer
in decem septuaginta novum in computatrum
right
iustum
the 1070 has over 1,900 cores Wow just
quod est super 1,900 MLXX sicut Wow millia metretas
get your header right up for a second
ut caput capitis recta sursum in vestri secundus
yeah they built this to be screaming
memini hoc fecerunt eiulare
fast 3d graphics and virtual reality it
3D virtualis re ieiunium graphics
is extremely fast because it is a
maxime ieiunium, quod factum est
different target of what it does but now
alium scopum facit, ut ea quae nunc
it's evolved to the point where they're
evolved ad, ubi suus 'iam non es
creating architectures based on this GPU
architectures creando secundum hoc GPU
platform to allow executable
ne tribunal exsecutabile
applications on this platform to tell
applications in hoc loco dicere
you like AI like AI would be a perfect
AI AI sicut vis perfectus esse
example okay because AI has to think
exempli bene habet quod cogitare intellegentiae artificialis
really really quickly in order to be
vere realiter esse ut celeriter
responsive like a human otherwise you're
aliter humana dociles, sicut tu
waiting for it and it's not realistic so
expectantes et ut suus 'realis
by using GPUs we now have not just eight
Nunc nos iustus have non utendo GPUs octo
threads of information that we can think
quia non possumus cogitare de notitia relatorum
about at one given time very very
De eodem tempore ipsum
quickly Alvia we have thousands upon
cito Alvia habemus ad milia
thousands of threads right that can be
ut ius potest esse relatorum milia
thought about by that processor at any
cogitatur ab aliquo processus
given time sort of reminds me of like
dedit tempus admonuit generis tamquam me
right brain and left brain they're two
ius cerebrum reliquit cerebrum et tu non duos
different components of the computer so
ut computatrum ad alia components
but one was built on the brain was built
aedificavit autem cerebri structum
for what they call the soul right the
quales nominant iure
gaming you know the power the where it
gaming nosti in quibus potestatem
gets its power from but now that you can
nunc autem habet virtutem ex potestis
now run things on the GPU like a server
Nunc quæ decurrunt in GPU sicut servo
mm-hm mm-hm
m-mm mm-m
and I do my rendering in blender on the
et facies mihi in blender in reddendo
GPU and oh my goodness is that ever fast
Heu mihi quia bonitas semper est GPU et ieiunium
right compared to CPU C and ridiculous
comparari recta C memoriae CPU
and that's why you wanna have a really
et quod suus 'a vere quid habes
good graphics that's why we didn't cheap
ideo bene nos putes graphics
out on the graphics
in graphics sunt
no right it's all it's almost become the
ius nullum actum suus 'fere facti sunt
most important component I remember it
maxime component ea meminisse me
for the longest time it was the
quia in longissimum tempus sit
motherboard and the CPU were the two
et duo motherboard Pentium
like the two components you put all your
sicut duo vexasti universum populum
money into now it's like I could spend
Sed expendere pecuniam posset similis
five hundred bucks on those two combined
quingenti leones super utrumque
but I got spent six hundred on just the
nisi tantum centum sex censeo
graphics yeah just because of how
Quam ob graphics sicut yeah
important it's become and we did it may
et facti momenti fecit ut suus '
sound like science fiction but
et canetis sicut scientia ficta
researchers are closing in on the
per inquisitores sunt in claudendo
creation of an ingestible robot that can
creatio autem est robot quod potest ingestible
perform a variety of functions from
praestare variis ex munera
within the human body the International
in corpore humano International
Conference on intelligent robots and
Et ex colloquio intelligentes robots
systems in Vancouver earlier this month
Vancouver systems antea mense isto
researchers from Switzerland presented a
Inquisitores enim de Helvetia presented
prototype of a gelatin based actuator
exemplum etiam secundum actus GELATINA
actuators are the components that allow
sunt elementa patiantur Actuators
a mechanism to physically move so while
dum corporaliter movetur machinamentum
doctors can already insert machines like
sicut etiam medici iam inserere machinis
pacemakers into your body
in corpore Pacemakers
those are stationary and also require
his statiuis, et etiam requirere
invasive surgery it's unlikely that the
Psidium manu ejus 'probabile quod
gelatin robots are very tasty but they
sed fac esse robots gelatinam
would have a wide variety of
ut a varietate
applications the researchers in their
applications et inquisitores in
paper explained that the components of
components quod explicavit in charta
such edible robots could be mixed with
quae mandi possunt misceri robots
nutrients or pharmaceutical components
alimenta seu pharmaceutical components
for digestion and metabolism metabolism
metabolismus, digestio et metabolismi
potential applications are disposable
potentiale applications, sunt PROMPTU
robots for exploration digestible robots
robots quia exploratio robots digestionis,
for medical purposes in humans and
et in hominibus, et in medicorum proposita
animals and food transportation where
vbi nulla animalia cibum
the robot does not require additional
et non eget robot additional
payload because the robot is the food
nam cibus payload robot
researchers write as well fully edible
Inquisitores etiam plene mandi possunt scribere,
robots would help to study how wild
Quam studere robots ut auxilium feram
animals collectively behave the robots
animalibus in communi robots conversari
could also take a role of animal prey to
etiam accipere a partes in salutem animalis,
observe their hunting behaviors or a
venandi aut tenueris et se gerendi rationibus
trained protected animals to do
exercitatus facere animalia protected
predation and of course once medical
et medici aliquando utique predation
components are mixed into the edible
components sunt in mixto quam edimus, folliculum
composition the robots could help
robots compositionem non auxilium
preservation of wild animals or heal the
fera animalia salva vel ad sanandum
inside of the human body so neat that's
et intus in humano corpore quod tersus
a lot to digest
multum digereretur;
okay so anybody who's watched the show
Videbas ita quisquam bene ostendit quis
long enough knows that when it comes to
quod fit dum nescit
robots I'm a little bit skeptical but
robots ego judicio incredulus sed exigua,
okay so it's a gel casing which should
unde oportet quod illud vulgare purus armamentis
be disliked it's not a gel casing it is
iam fastidium est non vulgare sit alligatae armamentis
gel what made up right but that's
gel quod rectum est sursum, sed ut '
digestible so when it comes to the metal
ita fit metallum digestionis
components Oh like yeah are there here's
O components similis est hic est qui yeah
the fact is that they and when I say
Et hoc est quod dico
they scientists don't apples yeah folks
scientists folks sunt non apples yeah
that are in the know with this stuff and
hoc autem scito quod in supellectilem et
that are researching this stuff have
quae est ista quae researching
been developing digestible biodegradable
LAEVIS developing est biodegradable
electronic components so we're talking
electronic components ut erant 'loquitur
resistors and capacitors that are
Ergo resistor lineatus et qui capacitors
digestible right so they're not made of
ipsi erant 'non e iure et digestionis,
metal they're made of other organic
alterum metallum ipsi erant 'e organicum
compounds so that makes sense if that
et si facit sensu suis Revolutionibus componit
makes sense but the fact is is you give
sed hoc est quod facit sensu dabis
yourself a Raspberry Pi microcomputer
RUBUS IDAEUS Pi te esse microcomputer
and it can do a lot of stuff but it
et non potest facere nisi quod multus of supellectilem
doesn't I'm not eating my right doesn't
Im 'non rectum me non comedere non
yeah it doesn't do any physical movement
yeah non facere aliqua corporalis motus
right there's no physical movement an
illic 'nullum ius corporalis motus est
actuator is required in order to do the
actus qui requiritur in hoc quod facere
physical movement so what we now have is
motus corporis, ita quod iam non est
something that can take these edible
accipere aliqua huiusmodi quae mandi possunt,
components that could make electronic
components et potest facere electronic
things like you said you can get a
quæ ait vos can adepto a similis tui
pacemaker but somebody has to open up
nisi quis pacemaker habet aperire
and put it in right so instead let's say
atque in dextera tam pro lets 'narro
here's the pacemaker which has no
hic est, qui non habet pacemaker
mobility of its own and make it mobile
et mobile suum opum eam
make it so that it can walk its way into
ambulate in viam suam facere potest, ne illud
your heart right just have like a little
sicut est cor tuum rectum, sicut paulo
nano robot that can just go in and maybe
Nano robot qui iustus vado in quod maybe
heal your heart maybe your heart just
sana cor tuum sicut cor tuum maybe
needs a little bit of extra these these
paulum ex his opus habet extra hos
these edible components though are not
quamquam sunt haec components mandi possunt
mobile don't put an actuator on it now
Nunc illud est actus mobilis ne dimittas
all of a sudden they become a mobile
mobili repente fiunt
yeah where would it store the infant
yeah quo congregem quod esset infantulus
like it's collecting information
colligendis notitia ut suus '
potentially if it's for health purposes
est in potentia nisi ad salutem proposita
where does it store this information
in quo enim haec notitia repono
how'd it like man how do you cover it
sciebas eam quasi homo, ut tu eam
still really early in the
usque in mane vere
kind of the announcement phase of this
nuntiatum est quaedam pars
technology but I think you know there
sed puto te scire technology est
there are technologies like Bluetooth
sunt sicut technologiae Bluetooth
and being able to sync to a mobile
Et non poterant ad sync mobili
device or something like that is that
aut sicut aliquid, quod illa fabrica
possible with organic technology I don't
cum ego non fieri potest organicum technology
know could it be like we've heard of
sicut nos audivimus et possit fieri scitote intelligentes
Microsoft using DNA strands to store
Microsoft est usura DNA canalibus thesaurizantes
data i I would say I love this idea for
ideam hanc de notitia amo ego volo dicere,
a lot of reasons when we come to like
multum similis nobis causas
using it for human healing and that sure
per ea homo ad sanitatem, et fideles
I don't love the idea of changing
Non amat ideam de mutantur
anything in wildlife like I don't know
aliquid simile apud bestias nescio
so what are you just I don't know I feel
et quid vos iustus sentio nescio
like we can make I guess the we can
EGO coniecto ut possumus facere quod possumus
consent and they can't so even if it's
et consensu non tam si suus '
an endangered species hold on hold on
periclitatur species tenuit tenebit
you're concerned about impacting
Es vos sollicitus super impacting
wildlife with a gel robot that would
quod si et bestias gel robot
heal with them when when you look at all
cunctis videntibus et sanem eos
across the globe
trans globe
no no all of the ecosystems and animals
no animalium omnium Ecosystems
we've destroyed and you concern about a
et de diximus de destrui
robot kind of mixed up here so yes ok
Etiam urna admisceri genus huc robot
talk about predation think about
loqui videtur de predation
domesticated or not even domesticated
neque mansueti generis, ne quidem domestico
but think about a center that helps
qui autem cogitant de medio adjuvat
animals that are either endangered or
aut animalibus et periclitabantur
perhaps they've been injured and they
fortasse deterioratus est et mihi ipsi
bring them back to health
sanitatem revocare
now that animal is now acclimated to
nunc autem animalis non est acclimated
human contact it is able to it's not
contactum hominis sit suus 'non potest
able to go back into the wild because we
quod possit ire ad feram
know it will die because it will become
sciunt enim quod mori fiet
the prey right I made the logically if I
Et fecit rectum in futurum si logically
get it you know if they were to get to
vos enim nostis ut, si essent ut ad
create edible robots now as a vegetarian
creare autem quasi leo robots mandi possunt
you can appreciate this now we have a
te potest appreciate quod nunc habemus
prey that is programmable that the
programmable ut non praeda,
predator this human acclimated animal
Predator Omnibus quod animalis homo acclimated
that we're trying to bring back to
qui erant adducere conatur ad
predator
predator
instincts can attack this robot and eat
comede hoc possint motus robot
it and it can be digested and it can
et concoqui possit: et potest
have nutrients but they're not actually
sed tu habent nutrimentum in actu,
affecting other animals in that process
processus circa alia animalia in eo
and acclimating them back to predatory
et praedatorias reduces acclimating
instincts so that they can be re
ut re naturali potest
replaced into their original habitat
Habitat in pristinum locum
that's just one idea it's an interesting
Unum est quod idea amet
concept I am all-in now it's not like
Ego autem in conceptu omnium, suus 'non amo
they're that they're feeding animals
quod illi tu es animalibus
these they're like becoming otamatone I
hi sunt, ut tu fieres otamatone
don't parasitic strange robots no all
nec mirum omnibus robots ne parasiticis
right a couple in the US have admitted
et non admisit duobus dextra in US
stealing goods from Amazon valued at
furtum de bonis Amazon aestimatum
more than 1.2 million dollars by
magis quam 1.2 million pupa per
repeatedly pretending that the items
saepe esse commentum items
they ordered were damaged in the post oh
O iusserunt deformarentur posti
no a couple from Indiana have pleaded
Non enim ex duobus Indiana egissem,
guilty to postal fraud and money
Praesent pretium fraudis reus
laundering the couple faces fines of up
sursum autem a duobus lavare facies tuas multas
to $500,000 as well as prison sentences
ad $ 500,000 tum sententias carcerem
of up to 20 years do not mess with
et usque ad XX annos non tatam cum
Amazon according to a local newspaper
Amazon secundum ad loci diurna
the Muncie Star Press they used hundreds
et Muncie stella solebant centum Press
of false online added identities to
et addiderunt identitas online falsa est
order popular tech gadgets from Amazon
ut vulgaris ab Amazon tech Gadgets
including Samsung smartwatches GoPro
inter Samsung smartwatches GoPro
cameras and Xbox Xbox video game
cameras et videos feras Xbox Xbox
consoles the couple then contacted
in duobus ergo solatur contingi
Amazon's customer service department to
Amazon scriptor mos muneris department est
report that the items have a had arrived
quia venit a se referunt ad items
damaged or were not working and Amazon
non laedi opere Amazon
sent out replacement products for free
postea misit products for free
they then sold the merchandise to
tunc merces vendidit
another individual who resold the
qui autem singula alia resold
products to an unnamed firm based in New
sine nomine firm products ad fundatur in novae
York the couple and their accomplice
Et in duobus Eboracum consenciens
were eventually caught after a joint
demum captus post iuncturam
investigation conducted by the US Postal
inquisitio ab Q. Fabio Maximo US tabellarios
Inspection Service Indiana State Police
Aliquam publicae Indiana inspectionem Service
and the Internal Revenue Service hmm Wow
et Internum VECTIGAL Officium hmm Wow
so yeah what kind of trail would they
sequor et qua memini et volo
have to leave like to get caught well
ut non discedere atque ad adepto deprensus
yeah must have had to be backwards
yeah habuisse necesse est retrorsum
it must have been that they found the
non est inventus qui se fuisse
New York final sale place and then went
Venetiis ultima est sale et abierunt
backwards maybe you think so the fact
eo retro: maybe non puto
that the Postal Service is involved
quod est involved tabellarios
makes me wonder if well these folks
istorum magis miror bene
would have been receiving a lot of
recepta fuisset multum
packages right one point two million
dextera autem parte duo decies packages
dollars worth so would Amazon if it said
ideo dicitur quod non valet nisi Amazon dollars
they're gone hmm
hmm abiit ipsi erant '
we have 800 customers all living at the
customers DCCC habemus ad omnem animam viventem
same address like or something maybe
aut aliquid simile sicut oratio maybe
even still like that would flag you to a
et tamen simile volunt, ut a vexillum ut
certain area is getting a ton of I mean
quidam non intelliguntur a ton of area questus est
sure like even if you lived in a place
ut si certo et vixit in loco,
like New York City to turn around and
ut autem revertimini et abite in New York City
say you know there's 800 accounts all
quia dicis quod illic 'DCCC rationum omnium
having the same issues with tech in New
apud eundem, having proventus per tech Novum
York City where this has never happened
In quo hoc nunquam factum est York City
before like that would be a flight with
ut esset ante fugam
some sort sure that aside though I mean
quod etsi non sit certa quaedam declinant
you think about their delivery system
cogitare de partum in vestri ratio
when they're bringing it by air and they
ubi erant ex aere et tollens illud
got drones and stuff but and how much
ignavom fucos pecus, et non obtinuit quam multa et supellectilem
more so are people gonna be tempted to
et sic magis ad tentandum amet
grab that drone and run away with the
Et capto illo fugiendum ad pabula fucus
product mm-hmm right I never thought of
Numquam cogitatur de iure productum mm, hmm
doing this I never even thought of
Numquam hoc cogitarat
returning anything I was on but I bought
reversus est autem quid ego faciam emit
a juicer yes and it was a lifetime
et factum est, quod sic vita juicer
warranty juicer so I could have easily
tam facile possim juicer warantum
contacted the manufacturer and and just
contingitur, et justum, et manufacturer
replaced a part but I asked Amazon and
pars autem rogavi pro Amazon et
they said no boson makes it easy
facit facile negarent Boson
yeah Amazon said well do it this way
Amazon est sic dicitur non bene yeah
it's been within 24 hours of you
suus 'fuisse XXIV horas inter vos
receiving the product just return it no
et accipiens productum est iustus non revertetur
problem I've returned things weeks later
Ego forsit post hebdomades res rediit
and they yeah anything and everything so
Gaudete et sic quodlibet
if it's that easy to return it so who's
Si quis est tam facile reverti
who takes the fall
qui tollis ruinam
it's the sellers so you think about
suus 'fere exigo ut putas,
Amazon you think oh that's a great
Amazon putas, O magnum quod
online store well no it's really an
Bene quod suus 'vere est non online store
online shopping mall let's say because
quod online shopping vir lets 'narro
the sellers that you're buying from are
quia tu es buying a in exigo
other companies and they're selling
alias societates et tu vendere
their products and products that they
et products quod eorum products
warehouse to you as basically a dropship
CELLA vobis quod basically Dropship
kind of arrangement with Amazon Amazon
cum talis dispositio Amazon
is the storefront and they are pushing
et non est storefront propellentibus
out their products so if I buy a product
si ex eorum products ut emere productum
as let's say I'm this malicious user and
ut lets 'narro EGO Im' et hic usor malicious
I buy that product and I claim that it's
Ego buy quod productum est, et affirmant
broken and they send me another one
et mihi aliud conteri
now that company is down
turba ergo quae est deorsum
Amazon always favors in the in favor of
Amazon semper adiuvat in in favorem Dei
the buyer not the seller so I can make
sicut emens, sic ille qui vendit non possum facere
up any nonsense you know something
scitis quod in aliqua ineptias
something was broken and they'll replace
aliquo loco rupta advenero
it
quod
that's Amazon's policy it's all right
Amazon est consilium quod actum est iustum
buyer is number one and it's fantastic
Numerus est unum et reddet emptori quod suus 'fantastic
as a consumer to be able to have that
pro dolor, qui esse possit habere
kind of service but it really can burn
adolebitque ea re potest, sed quaedam opera
in a case like this where hey if I was a
in hoc casu, ubi quasi heus si essem
seller that would knock me out of
pulsate, qui vendit non ex me,
business
negotium
right so I sent my juicer back yeah but
Habemus autem memini misi ad juicer
I wouldn't have had to is that the way
Et non erat qui est in via
is that the case of a you've sent him
si autem a te missus est in eo
back for what / why why did you send it
retributio enim / Quare cur eam
back I returned it and then just bought
Redii deinde it retro, et mox emit
a new one is there something wrong why
quare nefas est unum aliquid novi
there was a part you needed to replace
opus est tibi pars reponere
yeah there was a part it was a part that
memini enim pars est pars
was broken okay so I could have so that
ita ut bene confractum potui
returned it that's different than buyer
reversi sunt ut 'non aliud quam emit
remorse by Errol Morris is getting the
questus est, quod per conscientiam Errol Boethius
juicer and saying hmmm I kind of wish it
Scriptum est mihi dicens Juicer quaedam vis
was pink right and returning it for that
et quod rectum est reversus fuerat rosea
reason now they can't sell it again they
Iam illud quod non est vendere
can't sell it as new because its users
ut quod suum novum users can not sell
too now but this couple would get
sed etiam iam esse ut duobus
doubles of each thing so how did they
unde factum duplici singula
how do they not have to send back that's
quomodo non remittere quod
my question did I not have to send back
Non hercle ego remittere
my juicer but just did out of honesty
juicer meum, et fecit ex justo justo
because it was broken Wow right yeah I
Curabitur ut recte memini quod destructum fuerat
don't maybe you don't have to I know
maybe vos non habent ut non novi
that I have had a case before where I
quia ante casum habuisse ubi
ordered some pillowcases they were
quosdam autem Comment
coming from China they it's it took a
Tulitque eum de Sina venit autem vir suus '
long time yeah I've heard and then they
Ego audivi et non diu yeah
sent me another order well then I had
et bene mihi erat missus
two of them right right hmm and I have
Hmm habeo duos right
had similar instances happen that
et similia fieri
happened with a mouse for me great it's
Magna est enim contigit mus
like I'm not doing I don't do those
Im 'non faciens ut non faciatis ea
things for out of them but now that you
Nunc vero ex istis
make it yeah I'm like yeah that has
yeah facite quae non sum similis yeah
happened where something doesn't arrive
quod ubi factum est, non perveniet
so then how did they change their policy
sic igitur quomodo ad mutare consilium suum
in a way to add that extra level of
quod in via extra campester of addere
difficulty detection for the seller
ob difficultatem deprehendatur venditor
right I know that I OtterBox used to
Scio me ius ad OtterBox
have it so that if your phone case was
quod si non est ita causa fuit vestri telephonum
broken they would replace it no
non fractum esse repone
questions asked as long as you took a
interrogavit quaestiones de tulit omnibus diebus vitae tuae
picture of the broken brace and centroid
et ibit imago ue fragmentis
yeah so maybe that's the case maybe you
ita maybe qui est casus maybe vos yeah
take the picture of whatever it is
quidquid acceperint imaginem
proving that it's not usable yeah and
et ostensum quod suus 'non utilis yeah
then you don't have to return it because
quia tunc non reddere
it's clearly not usable okay I bought a
scilicet quod suus 'non utilis ut bene sit emit
product for our dog and the company that
productum pro nobis ut canis et societatem
we bought it from actually sent the
emit enim, ex hoc misit ad nos
wrong thing so I contacted Amazon and
nefas est, ut Amazon et ego contingi
said the wrong product was sent and it
et dixit iniuria uber missus
was it was arrived directly from Amazon
factum e venisse Amazon
it wasn't from the like the private
Non quasi ex propria
retailer and the response I got from the
et responsionis obtinuit me ab retailer
individual I was talking to was okay
singula autem cœpissem loqui, cum bene
well just throw that one out we'll send
Qui autem unum dimittam puteum iactare
you the proper one yeah and I'm like
yeah propriis tibi unum, sicut et ego
just throw it out you don't want it back
sicut et projice abs te nolo eam
it's not worth it this is this is kind
suus 'non dignitas is id quod est genus suum
of the case right so there needs to be a
utique oportet justum esse et
way that saves people yeah get you
ut te salvet populum yeah
thinking caps on
ratus PILLEATOS
big thanks to Roy W Nash in our
John magnas gratias W Nash nostri
community of viewers for submitting
conventu et pro exhibenda viewers
stories us this week thanks for watching
tibi gratias ago pro nostrum quod spectant fabulas sabbati
the category-five TV newsroom don't
TV quinque-genus non newsroom
forget to Like and subscribe for all
et velut oblivisci omnium subscribe
your tech news with a slight linux' bias
tech tibi nuntium aut levi Linux 'Praeiudicia
and for more free content be sure to
et magis liberum esse certa ad contentus
check out our website from the
Lorem a website
category-five TV newsroom I'm Sasha
Quinque-genus TV newsroom me Sasha
Rickman Thank You Sasha
Tibi gratias ago tibi Not Rickman
this is category 5 technology TV and
V genus technology, et hoc TV
hope you've enjoyed yourself tonight we
Speremus te nocte fruendum te ipsum et nos
are flat at a time but really looking
sunt plana, sed ad tempus vere bellus
forward to being here again with you
Hic enim cum prospiceret
next week and I hope you can join us now
nos autem sabbati et tunc spero vos iungere potest
I want to say thank you for those of you
Volo dicere gratias ago tibi, quia illa de vobis
who have been supporting us through
quae sunt per nos supporting
patreon you'll see the links on our
Nexus ad patreon youll 'animadverto pro nobis
website category 5 TV but it's a really
V genus website TV suus 'non a vere
great way that you can support category
ut possitis sustinere maximum genus
5 we do this we offer this as a free
V Hoc enim volumus quod et nobis offerre libera
show for you and we hope that you enjoy
ut ostenderet tibi quod speramus frui
it and we love to interact with you but
et amamus, sed ut penitus per vestri
it does cost a lot of money so that is
id est poena et opibus
one way that you can pitch in in a fun
Metabuntur autem in uno posse amet
way with some rewards there to make it
quodam modo enim pretium ut
worth your time and we look forward to
Operae pretium est tempus et expectamus
having you as a part of our patronage at
quod apud te patrocinia pars
patreon so thank you very much to those
gratias ago tibi, et diversi generis multa nimis illis patreon
who are doing that yes that's all the
Nam qui hoc faciunt omnes
time that we have YouTube
in tempore illo nos habere YouTube
great stuff tonight thanks so much for
hac materia agentes tam magna
being here Travis
Cogito Ergo hic esse
I'll see you say next Wednesday night
Et tu dicis videatur Mercurii proximo noctis
good night
bonum nocte
[Music]
[Musica]